let's be honest it's the boring that
说实话，真正
makes you rich and the most unbelievable
让你致富的是那些看似枯燥乏味的事情。
way for generating wealth and long-term
创造财富和实现长期
Economic Security is and then once you
经济保障最不可思议的方法就是……一旦你
do that you can become a super tax
做到了这一点，你就可以成为一个超级避税
avoider that sounded awful Scott
者。这听起来很糟糕，但斯科特·
Galloway one of the world's leading
加洛韦（Scott Galloway）——世界
voices in business and finance is back
商业和金融界的领军人物之一——又回来了。
his mission is to help millions of
他的使命是帮助数百
people build incredible wealth and live
万人积累巨额财富，过上
a life of Economic Security if you're
经济保障的生活。如果你
trying to build wealth you want to lean
想积累财富，就要充分利用你的
into your advantages your advantages in
优势。20多
your 20s our flexibility and time so
岁时的优势是：灵活和时间充裕。所以要敢于冒险，
take risks find your talent not your
找到你的才能，而不是你的
passion that has a 90 plus% employment
热情（因为热情的就业率高达90%以上）。
rate or become an owner not an earner
或者，成为所有者，而不是赚钱者，
and develop an army of capital that goes
打造一支
out and kills for you at night and then
为你夜夜奔波的资本大军，然后
invest it what if you're not young focus
进行投资。如果你不再年轻怎么办？那就专注于你
on the things you can control one thing
能控制的事情。你能控制的事情之一
that is within your control is spending
就是消费，
but 98% of us will spend everything we
但我们98%的人都会把所有能拿到手的钱都花光。要
get our hands on it is very hard to have
拥有
the discipline to take money that is
自律，把触手可及的钱拿出来
within your grasp and invest it and we
投资，是非常困难的。我们往往
don't appreciate the power of investing
低估了
in compound interest my team brought a
复利的力量。我的团队带来了
bucket of sand to illuminate the power
一桶沙子，来阐明复利的威力。
of compounding interest this is
这是指从
of 12 months starting at the age of 25
25岁开始，每月投资1000英镑，持续12个月。
if you left it and kept investing at
如果你坚持
that rate by the age of 65 it would look
这个投资速度，到65岁时，你的账户余额会是这样的。这位
this and the young man is says I have
年轻人说：“我有
500 lb I'm going to wait till I have a
500英镑，我要等到有100万英镑才
million before I start investing the way
开始投资。”
you get a million pounds is by investing
获得100万英镑的方法就是投资
that 500 and there notion that it's too
这500英镑。还有人认为“我已经40多岁了，现在投资
late for me I'm in my 40s I'm going to
太晚了，我打算
ignore finances oh bull so what is the
忽略财务问题”。胡说八道！那么，
set of steps let me make it easy first
具体步骤是什么呢？让我简单解释一下。首先，
congratulations Dio gang we've made some
恭喜各位Dio的听众，我们取得了一些
progress 63% of you that listen to this
进展。63%的
podcast regularly don't subscribe which
定期收听我们播客的听众没有订阅，
is down from
比之前的
69% our goal is 50% so if you've ever
69%有所下降。我们的目标是50%。所以，如果你
liked any of the videos we've posted if
喜欢我们发布的任何视频，或者
you like this channel can you do me a
喜欢这个频道，请帮我一个
quick favor and hit the Subscribe button
小忙，点击订阅按钮。
it helps this channel more than you know
这对频道的帮助远超你的想象。正如你所看到的，
and the bigger the channel gets as
频道越壮大，我们邀请的
you've seen the bigger the guests get
嘉宾就越重量级。
thank you and enjoy this episode
谢谢大家，祝你们收听愉快！
Scott you've written a book on wealth
斯科特，你写了一本关于财富、
money
金钱和
Finance why and why does it why does it
金融的书，为什么？为什么它如此
matter uh this is kind of a memo to my
重要？嗯，这算是写给
25-year-old
25岁的
self I've been Rich three times and the
自己的一份备忘录。我曾经三次富有，
first two times I lost it and I didn't
前两次都失去了财富，而且我并非出身富裕家庭。
very important to me I think America and
对我来说，财富非常重要。我认为美国，
mostly in Europe but especially America
尤其是欧洲，
America becomes more like itself every
越来越像它本身的样子：
if you have money it's a rapacious
如果你有钱，它是一个慷慨友爱的地方；
violent place if you don't I think
如果你没钱，它就会变成一个贪婪暴力的地方。我认为
Economic Security is really important
经济安全非常重要，
and I think there's a series of habits
而且我认为有一系列的习惯
and character traits that uh can help
和性格特征可以帮助
you get to Economic Security you know
你获得经济安全。你知道
that study that you become the average
那项研究吗？研究表明，你的经济状况会变成
of your five closest friends same body
你五个最亲密朋友的平均值，这些人拥有相同的体重
mass index same politics same sports
指数、相同的政治观点、相同的运动
team same
队以及相同的
neighborhood uh what they don't talk
居住地。但是，他们没有提到的
about is that amongst those five people
是，即使这五个人的收入大致
same amount of money one will end up
相同，最终也会有一个人
much more economically well off than the
比
other four and I'm trying to understand
其他四个人富裕得多。我试图理解，为什么最终能够获得
becomes economically secure by the time
经济安全的人会做出这样的行为。 像
they're my age without making a lot more
我这个年纪，收入
money than their
却比
colleagues do you think we're taught
同事高不了多少的人，你觉得我们从小就被教育要懂
about money where did where did those
钱吗？那些
people that one in five where did where
五分之一的人又是从哪里
did they learn about money yeah that's a
学来的？嗯，这确实是个
really interesting question I think so
很有意思的问题。说
the honest answer is I don't know what I
实话，我也不知道该怎么说。从
would say uh sociologically is that rich
社会学的角度来看，
people talk about money and it's
富人谈论金钱，而
considered taboo for employees and
员工、
middle class and lower class and women
中产阶级、下层阶级以及女性
to talk about money like you're told not
谈论金钱则被视为禁忌，比如
to talk about your salary at work
在工作中被告知不要谈论薪水。
asymmetry of information will always
信息不对称总是对掌握
that knows the information the boss of a
信息的人有利。
company knows what everyone's making but
公司老板知道每个人的收入，但
he tells his or her employees not to
他会告诉员工不要
discuss their salary because Lisa might
讨论薪水，因为丽莎可能会
found out that Bob is making 30% more
发现鲍勃做着同样的工作，收入却比她高出30%。
for doing the same work so there's a bit
所以，现在有一种风气，
of a zeit guy that tells people not to
告诫人们不要
talk about money that it's like talking
谈论金钱，说这就像
about porn or that it's vulgar and I
谈论色情片一样，或者说很粗俗。但我
think you need to start talking about
认为，你应该从小就开始谈论
money and maintain a certain level of
金钱，并保持一定的
financial literacy from a very early age
金融素养，
because Roger Federer talks about tennis
因为罗杰·费德勒也会谈论网球。
if you want to be good at anything most
如果你想打好网球，就应该从小就了解金钱。 大多数
people want to be good at money and to
人都想在理财方面有所建树，而
be good at something you need to
要想在某方面有所建树，你需要
understand it and to understand it you
了解它；要了解它，你
need to talk about it so I'm very
需要谈论它。所以我对自己的收入和支出都非常
transparent with how much money I make
坦诚。
what I do with it but talk to your
但你也应该和
friends about mortgage rates talk to
朋友们聊聊房贷利率，聊聊他们赚了
your friends about how much money they
多少钱，他们把钱花在了
make what they're doing with it where
哪里，
they lost money and and people aren't
以及他们哪里亏了钱。人们往往
transparent about it especially I think
对此不够坦诚，尤其是
about men we're supposed to be just like
男性，我们似乎应该“
accidentally wealthy and to ever talk
不劳而获”，谈论
about our financial problems is to admit
财务问题就等于承认
that we're not Ballers or that we're not
自己不是“大款”，或者不够“
masculine and so I encourage people from
男子气概”。所以我鼓励人们从小就
a young age to start talking about money
开始谈论金钱，
and understand it and be transparent
了解它，并坦诚地谈论
about it where did you learn about money
它。你是从哪里学到理财知识的呢？回想我
because I think about my own life and I
自己的人生，我
think there's key moments of quite
认为有些关键时刻，
frankly luck yeah where I was exposed to
坦白说，是运气使然。我接触到这些
information because I was invited into a
信息，可能是因为我被邀请进入某个
room physically literally into a room or
房间——真的是被邀请进入某个房间——或者并非
I was through no decision of my own
出于我自己的选择，
someone came into my life yeah um or in
某人走进了我的生活。嗯，就我而言，
blessings I ever had is when I went off
我最大的幸运之一或许就是当我从
dropped out of University and pursued
大学辍学去
entrepreneurship my brother decided to
创业时，我的哥哥决定…… 我
in London Y and then when I had my first
在伦敦当了11年的投资银行家，然后当我第一次成功
exit he messaged me one day and said hey
退出时，有一天他给我发信息说：“嘿，
I'll manage your money and I'll quit my
我会帮你管理资金，我会辞职，
job and come work with you full-time and
全职来帮你。” 他是
that's my older brother so like life
我哥哥。所以，生活
gave me the greatest gift anyone could
给了我一份任何人都能得到的最好的礼物，这真是太对了。
think of three things as you said that
正如你所说，我想到了三件事。
the first is the smartest thing I ever
第一件是我做过的最明智的事，那就是
did was being born a white heterosexual
出生在60年代的加州，而且是个白人异性恋
male in California in the 60s because it
男性，因为这
gave me unfair Advantage it gave me
给了我不公平的优势。我可以
access to free education the University
免费接受教育，进入
of California and access 76% admissions
加州大学，而且当年
rate when I applied UCLA the admissions
我申请加州大学洛杉矶分校时，录取率高达76%，而
rate this year is 9% I came a
今年的录取率只有9%。我
professional age in the 90s when the
在90年代进入
internet was coming online so I sort of
职场，那时互联网正在兴起，所以我算是
had these winds in my back and also so
顺风顺水。坦白说，
just to be blunt everyone that was
所有
raised in capital looked smelled and
在资本环境中长大的人看起来、闻起来、
felt like me they were all white
感觉起来都和我一样，他们都是白人
heterosexual males and I didn't even
异性恋男性。当时我甚至没有
realize at the time what privilege or
意识到自己拥有多么大的特权或
unfair Advantage I had so the first is
不公平的优势。所以第一件
just just sheer luck the second is
纯粹是运气。第二件是……
environmental I grew I was raised by a
我成长的环境让我意识到，我由一位
single immigrant mother who lived in die
单身移民母亲抚养长大，她住在……（此处原文疑似拼写错误，无法准确翻译）。那些在富裕环境中长大的
up with money people who grow up with
人，
money just can't really truly empathize
很难真正体会到贫困的滋味。
money I felt as if there was this ghost
我感觉好像有个幽灵一直
following me and my mom around
跟着我和我妈妈，
constantly whispering in our ear you're
在我们耳边低语：“你
not worthy your mom [__] up which
不配，你妈妈搞砸了，这
means you you aren't worthy and so I
意味着你不配。” 因此，我
very early decided that I was that
很早就意识到
Economic Security was really important
经济保障
to me I want to be clear you can't make
对我来说至关重要。我想澄清一点，
a decision to be wealthy a lot of it is
致富并非一蹴而就，很多时候靠
luck but I was going to be very
运气。但我会为此付出巨大的努力。我
committed my goal in life from 0 to 45
从零到四十五岁的人生目标
wasn't to be a good person it wasn't to
不是做一个好人，不是
save the whales it wasn't to to have
拯救鲸鱼，也不是拥有
strong relationships it was to get
牢固的人际关系，而是获得
economic security so I started
经济保障。所以我
connecting the dots around money pretty
很
early and then along the lines of what
早就开始把金钱和生活联系起来。然后，就像
you were talking
你刚才说的，
about um my mom had a boyfriend and um
我妈妈有个男朋友，你
know how in certain dramas they
知道，人们很少谈论这种事，就像某些电视剧里会
reference a second family where a guy
提到“第二个家庭”，一个男人在……
has an entirely other family despite the
之外还有另一个家庭。
fact he's married my mom and I were that
他娶了我妈妈，而我成了他的
second family her boyfriend for seven
第二个家。我妈妈交往七年的男朋友
years was a wonderful man named Terry
叫特里，是个很棒的人，
really nice to me spent every other
对我特别好，每隔一个
weekend with us super generous to me uh
周末就来我们家，对我特别慷慨。呃，
he was also married with another family
他当时也已婚，有自己的家庭，
so we were that second family but he was
所以我们成了他的第二个家。但他是个
a good man and he was he was actually a
好人，实际上是
good role model for me and one weekend I
我的榜样。有一次周末，我
was asking him what is a stock and I was
问他什么是股票，​​当时我
13 and he said here's $200 he gave me
13岁。他说：“给你200美元。”他给了我
two crisp $0000 bills and said walk down
两张崭新的1000美元钞票，说：“去
fancy stock brokerages in Westwood
西木村那些高档的股票经纪公司买点
Village and buy some stock and if you
股票。如果你
don't buy it by Monday afternoon or by
周一下午之前或者我下
the time I'm back next weekend I'm
周末回来之前没买，我就把
taking my money back so at 13 I marched
钱拿回来。”于是13岁的我大摇大摆地去了
down to Marl Lynch Pierce Fenner Smith
马尔林·皮尔斯·芬纳·史密斯公司，当时
was in the lobby I was ignored I got
大厅里都是他们的员工。我被他们无视了，感觉有点
intimidated I walked across the street
害怕。我走到街对面，去了
to Dean Witter Reynolds another
另一家经纪公司迪安·维特·雷诺兹公司。一个
brokerage and this young guy named siero
叫塞罗的年轻人
came walking out and said hi I'm cero
走了出来，说：“你好，我是塞罗。”然后
and he gave me my first lesson in the
他给了我人生中的第一堂课。
markets and I bought 14 shares of
市场啊，我买了14股
Columbia Pictures I 13 He gave you a
哥伦比亚影业的股票。13岁的时候，他给我上了一堂
lesson in the market yeah at 13 and
股市课。是啊，13岁那年，
every day every weekday for the next
接下来的三年里，每个工作日，
phone booth I'd put two dimes in and
我都会从埃默森初中的公用电话亭投币，然后
call saigh and he would say Close
打电话过去。他会说《
Encounters of the Third is a hit which
第三类接触》票房大卖，这
means the Columbia uh Studios is going
意味着哥伦比亚影业要
to make a lot of money so people are
赚大钱了，所以大家都在
buying more stock and then I'd go into
买股票。然后我就去
his office I didn't I have a ton of
他的办公室。我没有那么多
friends and so I would just swing by
朋友，所以我经常去
Dean Witter and he would always give me
迪安·维特那里，他总是给我上一堂
markets had those two men not shown such
股市课。如果那两个人没有那么
generosity to you with that time and
慷慨地给了你时间和
with that $200 bill have you ever played
那200美元，你有没有在
out in your mind where you might be I
脑海里设想过自己可能会走到哪一步？我
think we all do that like sliding doors
想我们都会这么做，就像
that movie you know things are it's like
电影《滑动门》里那样。你知道，
life is such a ser series of you know I
人生就像一系列的……你知道吗？我当时就想，
I promised myself I was going to
我要在
Raleigh Hotel in the middle of the day
白天去罗利酒店搭讪那个坐在
who was sitting by the pool who was
泳池边的陌生女人，她当时
sitting there with another woman and
和另一个女人和
another guy and without the benefit of
一个男人坐在一起，而且没有任何好处。 喝了酒之后，
conversation with a strange woman and I
跟一个陌生女人搭讪并不容易。我
walked out to get my car and I said I
出去取车，心想
promised myself I was going to speak to
我答应过自己一定要跟
her I was very drawn to a beautiful
她说话。我被一个漂亮的女人深深吸引，
woman so I went back in I just rolled
于是我又回到酒店，径直走到她面前，
right up and I said hi I'm Scott where
说：“嗨，我是斯科特，
are you guys from and this was at the
你们从哪里来？” 这事发生在
Raleigh Hotel long story short 18 months
罗利酒店。长话短说，18个月
later our first son's middle name is
后，我们大儿子的中间名就叫
Raleigh right right and what I tell
罗利，对吧？我常跟
people is that unless you're willing to
人说，除非你愿意
take an uncomfortable risk nothing
承担一些不舒服的风险，否则
wonderful is ever going to happen to you
美好的事情永远不会发生在你身上。
I mean a really uncomfortable risk what
我指的是真正不舒服的风险，
you're doing here is an uncomfortable
你现在做的就是一个不舒服的
risk it's public failure if it doesn't
风险。如果
work this podcast platform you're
你创办的这个播客平台失败了，那就是公开的失败。
starting you know this most people
你知道，大多数人都
aren't willing to take these risks and a
不愿意承担这样的风险。很多事情，我不想说得太深奥，但
of this comes down to a huge unlock for
对
me as been atheism I think I have a very
我来说，这一切都源于一个巨大的顿悟——无神论。我认为我对
solid grasp of the finite nature of life
生命的有限性有了非常深刻的理解。
you're a young man you're going to be my
你还年轻，转眼间就会变成我这个
age in an instant and the thing you're
年纪，你
going to recognize is that
会意识到这一点。
okay in 30 or 40 years everyone whose
好吧，  30年或40年后，所有
opinion you are worried about is going
你担心别人意见的人都会
to be dead and I have found that has
去世。我发现，意识到这一点
been an enormous unlock for me knowing
对我来说简直是解脱。我知道，在
that I'm going to some point sooner than
某个比
I'd like look into my kids eyes and know
我预想的更早的时刻，我会看着孩子的眼睛，意识到
our relationship is coming to an end so
我们的关系即将结束。所以
I'm comfortable expressing my emotions
我可以更自在地表达我的情感，更自在地
taking uncomfortable risks knowing that
承担风险。我知道，
if I call someone and ask them to invest
如果我打电话给某人，请他们投资；
if I approach a strange woman in a bar
如果我在酒吧里主动搭讪一位陌生的女士
and introduce myself if I call an
并自我介绍；如果我打电话给一位
employee who I would never think would
我从未想过会
consider working for me I'm not afraid
考虑为我工作的员工，我都不怕被
of rejection because I realized everyone
拒绝。因为我意识到，所有那些让
I'm worried about being shamed by is
我感到羞耻的人，
going to be dead soon and so am I and so
很快都会去世，我也会。所以，
why wouldn't you live out life why
为什么不尽情地生活？为什么
wouldn't you live out loud why wouldn't
不活得精彩？为什么不
you squeeze so much juice from this you
从这颗
know uh lemon called life it's really
名为“生命”的柠檬里榨取尽可能多的汁液？这
been an enormous unlock for me because
对我来说真的是一个巨大的解脱。因为正如“
the Reality Steve is that most people
现实史蒂夫”所说，大多数人都
are not willing to take uncomfortable
不愿意承担可能
risks that might result in public
导致公开羞辱的风险。被
rejected by a PO to express interest in
警察拒绝，或者对某人表达好感却遭到拒绝，这确实很尴尬。
embarrassing to try and raise money and
筹款被拒很尴尬，
business and not have it work the
创业失败也很尴尬。
majority of people aren't willing to
大多数人都不愿意
take those uncomfortable risks and the
承担这些令人不适的风险。而你之所以能获得
reason why you get outsized return is an
超额回报，是因为你是一位
entrepreneur the reason why you get
企业家。你之所以能获得
outsize returns when you're willing to
超额回报，是因为你愿意主动
approach strangers and ask your
接近陌生人，寻求
mentorship friendship Express romantic
指导、友谊，甚至表达爱意，
interest is because you are willing to
是因为你愿意
endure rejection the most
承受拒绝。
overcompensated people in any
在任何
organization
组织中，收入最高的
of the sales people in terms of how hard
莫过于销售人员，无论
and how smart they are how hard they
他们的努力程度和聪明才智如何，他们的薪酬都远超其应得的水平。毫无疑问，收入最高的人也是
compensation hands down the most
最令人
resents are the salespeople because they
反感的销售人员，因为他们
are willing to get out a big spoon and
愿意吃苦耐劳，甚至不惜一切代价。
[__] do not call me again okay so what
别再给我打电话了。所以
you're saying is I should follow up in a
你的意思是，我应该
couple weeks right that type of
几周后再联系你，对吗？那种
rejection that type of risk that type of
拒绝，那种风险，那种
public failure 99% of people are not
公开的失败，99%的人都
willing to endure I ran for sophomore
不愿意承受。我高中时竞选过高二、
Junior and senior class president in
高三和高四的班长，
high school I lost all three times and
三次都失败了。
based on my track record I decided I
基于我的竞选记录，我决定
should run for student body president
竞选学生会主席。
where I went out went on to wait for it
出去玩，继续等待，然后
lose and it never really got in the way
失败，但这从未真正影响
of my confidence you know and that's the
我的自信，你知道，这才是
key if you want and unfortunately young
关键。不幸的是，年轻
men are told you know don't try hard or
男性被告知不要努力，否则
they feel like a loss of agency or
他们会感到失去主动权，尤其是在
especially romantically they're told be
恋爱方面，他们被告知要
careful in terms of expressing romantic
谨慎表达爱意。
interest and if you don't know the
如果你分不清
in asking someone out for coffee and
邀请某人喝咖啡和
harassing them you've got bigger
骚扰之间的区别，那你就有更大的
problems but I think a lot of young men
问题了。但我认为很多年轻男性
feel like their agency has been taken
感觉自己的主动权被
away they feel like the game is rigged
剥夺了，他们觉得游戏规则被操纵了，
so they're not trying and quite frankly
所以他们不去努力。坦白说，
they're spending much too too much time
他们把太多时间花在了
on a screen or in their home so they're
屏幕前或家里，所以他们
not putting themselves in a position to
没有让自己处于能够遇到美好事物的位置。
and on a very basic level I'm almost
从最基本的层面来说，我几乎可以
entirely sure that I can guarantee you
肯定地告诉你，
that nothing really want wonderful I
没有什么真正美好的事情会
mean really wonderful is going to happen
发生在你身上，我是说真正美好的事情。
your success is a function of your
你的成功取决于你
ability to endure rejection and
承受拒绝的能力，以及
increasingly how much time you spend
你花在屏幕外的时间越来越多。
if you're not young because what you
如果你不再年轻了呢？因为你
described there that all of that was me
描述的情况。 这一切都发生在我
18 I had just dropped out of University
18岁的时候。我刚从大学辍学，
after going to only one of the lectures
只上过一节课。
and I had these four credit cards which
我有四张信用卡，
had about I think combined about £1,000
加起来大概有1000英镑，全都
on them maxed them all out my parents
刷爆了。我爸妈跟
went speaking to me I'm 3 Hour 3 hours
我谈话。我离家大概三个小时，
trip in Manchester and I'm 18 I've have
在曼彻斯特，往返曼彻斯特要六个多小时。我才18岁，
got no kids no mortgage no nothing and
没有孩子，没有房贷，什么都没有，住在
I'm in this room that I can afford to
我能负担得起的房间里。所以，
pay for so in I was so clearly at the
我当时显然处于人生的
bottom with nothing to lose that every
谷底，没什么可失去的，每一次
roll of the dice was a potential win so
掷骰子都可能赢。所以
I was rolling that [__] but you
我拼命地掷骰子，一遍又一遍地掷，一遍又一遍地掷。
and over again but but I I I wonder
但是，我有时会想，
sometimes CU there's probably going to
也许
be someone listening that's you know 47
有人在听，47岁，
three kids mortgage comfortable job just
三个孩子，有房贷，一份勉强糊口的工作，
about cutting it every month one holiday
每个月勉强糊口，一年一次假期，他们也
dissatisfaction with their life but they
对自己的生活感到不满，但他们
can't roll like I could when I was 18
不能像我18岁时那样掷骰子。你
look the reality is when you have kids
看，现实是，当你有了孩子，
Everything Changes the I think the
一切都会改变。
probably the darkest Moment For Me Maybe
对我来说，最黑暗的时刻或许是
losing my mom was the moment that was
失去母亲之后，无论是个人生活还是职业生涯，最黑暗的时刻莫过于
when my first son was born and you think
我第一个儿子出生的时候。你以为当
that when this child when you you know
这个
this child's introduced to the world
孩子来到这个世界，一切都会像天堂一样，充满欢声笑语。然而，
angels singing for me if I felt
我却感到
humiliation and shame and fear because I
羞辱、难堪和恐惧，因为我
had made a lot of money but I had gone
赚了很多钱，但我却
Allin and this is a lesson from the book
孤注一掷。这正是我从《
The Power of diversification I'd gone
多元化的力量》这本书中学到的教训。我把所有资源都投入到了我创办的电商
Allin on this one company Red Envelope
公司Red Envelope上，这家公司于
which went public in 2002 as an
2002年上市。
e-commerce company I started and I
我当时的
thought and had been taught by The
想法，也是风险投资
Venture Capital Community that if you
界教给我的，就是如果你
throw yourself at something and your
全身心投入到某件事中，而且你很有
talented and I thought I'm a baller I'm
才华——我当时觉得自己很厉害，我真的很
really good at what I do you got to go
擅长我所做的事情——你就必须
all in and I kept investing every spare
全力以赴。我不断地把所有积蓄都投入到Red Envelope，一心
dollar I had and threw myself at this
扑在它上面。然而，
2008 our stock went from seven bucks to
2008年的港口罢工、软件故障和信贷危机，让我们的股价在短短三周内从7美元跌落到破产，
ended up not being worth 10 or 12
最终我…… 不是身价1000万或1200
million but being worth worth negative2
万，而是负200
million because I was one of those
万，因为我就是那种
idiots that borrowed against their stock
傻瓜，用股票作抵押
to buy more stock ah and then my child
去买更多股票。然后我的孩子，
has the poor judgment my oldest to come
我的大儿子，从
marching out of my girlfriend and the
我女朋友那里生了出来，
first thing I felt was failure on a
我当时的第一感觉就是巨大的失败。就像
my son was born was I have failed to
我儿子出生时我的第一反应一样，我没能尽到
live up to my core responsibility as a
作为男人最根本的责任——
man and that is to take care of my child
照顾我的孩子。那是一种非常
ugly emotion and that's a lesson in the
糟糕的感觉，也是个教训。当
book and that is the moment you
你
aggregate anything resembling some sort
积累了一笔
of uh decent amount of capital you want
可观的资金时，
to look at it and you want to diversify
你一定要好好审视它，并疯狂地分散投资。
like crazy because if I had just taken a
如果我当时拿出一些
little bit of money off the table and
钱去
invested in index funds or in real
投资指数基金、
estate or bonds
房地产或债券，
I would have been so much better off but
我的情况会好得多。但
everyone's told you can have it all you
每个人都说你可以拥有一切，你可以，
can you you
你
know you can be successful if you just
知道，只要你
go all in never give up well actually
全力以赴，永不放弃，你就能成功。但实际上，
the market Will trump individual
市场总是会胜过个人
performance every time and last week my
表现。上周，
the investment I was most excited about
我最兴奋的投资是
this healthc Care Tech startup great CEO
这家医疗保健公司。 一家医疗科技初创公司，CEO很棒，
tier one investors elbowed my way into
一流的投资人，他们想方设法让我参与进来，
the deal I put five million bucks in I
我投了五百万美元。
found out last Friday it's a zero it
上周五我发现这笔投资打了水漂，
just didn't work zero shutting
完全失败了，公司
down but here's the thing I never invest
倒闭了。但关键是，我
more than 3% of my net worth now in any
现在从不在任何单一项目上投资超过我净资产的3%。
one thing so while it hurts I have
所以，虽然很痛苦，但我有分散投资这种“
kevlar in the form of diversification so
防弹衣”。这就好比我
I took a bullet to the chest knocked me
胸口中了一枪，被打晕了，站都站不稳。我
out my feet I get up I was bummed out
爬起来，沮丧了
for an hour that was it because I never
一个小时，仅此而已。因为我从不孤注一掷。
go all in on something and people are
人们，
taught especially young people
尤其是年轻人，
especially men who are more risk
尤其是那些风险承受能力更强的男性，被教导要孤注一掷，
because the people who are the
因为
wealthiest people in the world kind of
世界上最富有的人似乎都是
went all in on something and what they
孤注一掷。但他们
don't tell you is the moment they have
没告诉你的是，一旦他们有了
Capital they start diversifying like
资金，就会疯狂地进行分散投资。
crazy so you want to diversify you don't
所以，如果你想分散投资，你不需要
need to find the needle and the Hast
找到那只“针”和“Hast
stack you can buy the whole Hast stack
Stack”，你可以买下整个Hast Stack。
and especially unfortunately in the
尤其是在
American economy not as much in the UK
美国经济，情况不太好，英国
economy it continues to be up and to the
经济则继续上涨，
right and the S&amp;P and the NASDAQ are
标普500指数和纳斯达克指数也都在上涨。
sort of self filtering mechanisms
自我过滤机制会
because they kick out companies that
淘汰
aren't great and they bring in new ones
不优秀的公司，引入新的公司。比如
they kick out Kodak and they bring in
淘汰柯达，引入
Salesforce if I had learned that divers
Salesforce。如果我年轻时就懂得多元化
ation when I was a younger man I would
投资，我就不会遭受那么多
have saved myself Not only would I be
损失了。我不仅能
have saved myself a lot of economic harm
避免很多经济损失，
I would have saved myself a lot of
还能避免很多
mental anguish so diversification and
精神痛苦。所以多元化投资，
that's one of the key components of my
这是我
algebra of wealth diversification people
财富多元化理论的关键组成部分之一。人们
don't recognize how powerful it is
没有意识到它的力量，
because it sounds boring and you have
因为它听起来很枯燥。
people like Bill Amman saying it's not
像比尔·阿曼这样的人会说，关键不在于
concentration it's conviction you know
专注，而在于信念。
and then they beat on their chest like
然后他们就自吹自擂，好像在
check out my [__] no divers ify and get
炫耀自己的财富。不要多元化投资，
rich slowly because here's the thing
慢慢致富。因为
life goes so goddamn fast W life has
人生苦短，谁会说人生过得很慢呢？再说，
your person who's 40 45 they're going to
40、45岁的人，他们还要
live another 40 years they're probably
活40年，可能
going to work another 30 you want to
还要工作30年。你应该
lean into your advantages your
发挥自己的优势。20
advantages in your 20s are flexibility
多岁时的优势是灵活性。
you want to Workshop careers find some
你应该灵活地规划职业生涯，找到
find your talent not your passion start
自己的才能，而不是仅仅追求激情，然后开始
saving a little bit of money a little
存钱。 年轻时攒下的一点钱，
when you're older trying to develop that
年老时就成了大数目。努力培养
savings muscle 100 bucks a month 1,000
储蓄能力，每月100美元，
bucks a month oh my God 2500 bucks a
每月1000美元。 我的天啊，每月2500美元！
month if you can do that in your 20s
如果你20多岁就能做到，那
you're going to be fine when you're my
你到了我这个年纪肯定没问题。
age even if you don't go double platinum
就算你没能成为双白金唱片歌手，没能
or sell a book or be a baller in
卖出一本书，也没能在
business you're fine your plan b is all
商界大展宏图，你也一样可以过得很好，你的B计划已经
set that's your advantage when you're in
准备就绪。这就是你
your 20s is time when you get to your 40
20多岁时的优势。到了40岁，
is your advantage is the following one
你的优势就变成了以下这一点：
hopefully you're in a relationship with
希望你那时能找到一个在
Financial um objectives your approach to
财务目标、
spending your approach to earning you
消费方式和赚钱方式上都能与你志同道合的伴侣。这样你
can see the Runway All right I'm going
就能看到未来的方向。好吧，我打算
to retire in 30 years I need 15 to 25
30年后退休，我需要
times my my nut to be in the bank to
在银行里存够我年收入的15到25倍才能
retire I spend about
退休。我
$120,000 a year that 20 times that I
每年大概花12万美元，那么20倍的年收入就是240万美元。
would need 2.4 million I'm not now work
现在我倒推一下，
million assuming 8% a year The Landing
假设年利率8%，我需要在接下来的30年里存多少钱才能达到240万美元？一切就绪，
lights are on you can start to plan your
你可以开始规划你的未来了。
life I'm not going to get there I can't
生活，我不可能达到那个目标，我
save this much I got kids in college
存不了这么多钱，我的孩子还在上大学。
okay when do your kids go to college can
好吧，你的孩子什么时候上大学？
you take that burn down to 80 grand by
你能不能通过
moving to Mexico City or Costa Rica or
搬到墨西哥城、哥斯达黎加或者
to St Louis but you have the advantage
圣路易斯，把支出降到8万美元？但你现在的优势在于你
of knowing your path ideally you have a
清楚自己的人生道路。理想情况下，你有一份
career where you can make some money and
可以赚钱的职业，可以
start saving a little bit ideally you
开始攒点钱；理想情况下，你
have a partner where you can get
还有一个伴侣，你们可以一起
alignment around working together to get
努力，实现
that Financial Security but most people
财务安全。但大多数
in their 40s are under the impression
40多岁的人都觉得
their life is over I mean they're
自己的人生已经结束了。我的意思是，他们
probably going to live to be over a 100
可能活到100多岁。
and so okay so you don't have 80 years
所以，好吧，你没有80年的时间，
you only have 60 years left but you
你只剩下60年了，但你
still probably got another 30 years
可能还有30年的时间
working and making money and you kind of
工作赚钱，而且你也
know what you need right uh so I think
知道自己需要什么，对吧？所以我认为
there's advantages at every age but this
每个年龄段都有优势，但那种“
notion that it's too late for me I'm in
我已经
my 40s I'm going to ignore finances a
40多岁了，太晚了，我要忽略财务”的想法纯属
[__] you just need to have an adult
胡扯。你需要
conversation with yourself do you think
和自己进行一次成熟的对话，你觉得
it makes sense then to go kind of risk
现在去冒险有意义吗？
on when you're young and then go
年轻的时候可以多投资，年纪大了就应该
Diversified once you're older because
分散投资，因为
you just want to highlight that for
我想强调的是，
people that are you know like I was when
像
I was 18 to kind of go all in and to
我18岁的时候那样，没什么可失去的就孤注一掷，孤注一掷。但
make those big bets when you have
一旦你有了需要
something to lose whether that's your
失去的东西，比如
Mor Gage you know you got children to
房贷、要
take care of or now you've got wealth to
养孩子，或者现在有了财富，就应该
then go risk off is that the kind of
规避风险。
approach you would suggest to
你会建议我采取这种人生观吗？
life I I think generally speaking you
我觉得一般来说，
have kids um when you're younger look if
有了孩子之后就不能像年轻时那样激进地冒险了。你看，就算
you screw up here you you're you're
你现在搞砸了，你人缘
you're likable enough that you can
也好，就算需要的话，你也能
probably find couches to live on for 2
找到地方借宿
years if you need it too if you like
两年。就算你
just got in over your
只是有点儿失控，
skis uh you could find a way to dance
你也能找到办法脱身。
when you're young you can dance Between
年轻的时候，你可以尽情享受生活。
The Raindrops I lived in New York I had
我住在纽约，
two two roommates when I started my
创业的时候和两个室友合租，
business my girlfriend paid our rent and
我女朋友帮我付房租，
I because I didn't I didn't have kids or
因为我当时没有孩子也没有
dogs there's just a certain level of
狗，所以……
take care of as you get older when you
随着年龄增长，责任和需要处理的事情也越来越多。年纪稍长一些后，
get a little bit older don't go all in
不要
on anything if you're going to start a
孤注一掷。如果你打算
business use other people's Capital ring
创业，可以利用别人的资金，做好资金
fence it don't get seduced into the
隔离，不要被诱惑。30
worst thing that can happen in your 30s
岁到40岁最糟糕的情况莫过于
and 40s is you start a business and you
创业后
start failing slowly you just don't know
慢慢失败，你根本无法预料。最
the worst type of business is one that
糟糕的创业方式就是那种
gives you just enough green signals that
给你一些看似有利的信号，让
you keep investing more time and more
你不断投入更多的时间和
money like Red Envelope people that's
金钱，就像“红包”项目一样，
what people know me for that's the worst
人们都知道我就是做这个的。这是最糟糕的
thing that can happen to somebody
情况，
because it failed slowly it failed over
因为它慢慢失败了。
11 years I started an e-commerce
我在纽约创办了一个电商
incubator in New York back by Goldman
孵化器，得到了高盛、摩根大通的支持，但
business in8 months because of the dot
8个月后就倒闭了，因为互联网泡沫
meltdown that's a blessing the best
破裂。这或许也算是一种幸运吧。最好的
thing that can happen is Success the
情况是成功，
second best thing is fast failure the
其次是快速失败，最
worst thing that can happen to you is
糟糕的情况是
slow failure you can't have slow failure
缓慢失败。30岁到40岁绝对不能承受缓慢失败，
in your 30s and 40s so you want to make
所以你要
sure that if you go in on something you
确保…… 当你投入某件事时，你要把它划为投资
ring fence it I'm leaving my job I'm
范围。我要辞职，我要
going to try and start my own business
尝试创业，
I'm going to spend two years doing it a
我打算花两年时间，投入
certain amount of capital no more than
一定数量的资金，
maybe 10 20% of my Capital because
大概不超过我全部资本的10%到20%。因为
hitting a wall and failing at 50 is is
50岁时遇到瓶颈或失败，
much more devastating than hitting a
比
wall or failing at 25 or 30 you can get
25岁或30岁时遇到瓶颈或失败要痛苦得多。你可以
up again you're fine you can press the
重新振作，没事的，你可以多次按下
restart button a bunch of times so you
重启键。所以你
want to take advantage of that in your
要在20多岁
20s and 30s and workshop a bunch of
和30多岁的时候好好利用这段时间，尝试各种各样的
things I'm not saying hop around I'm not
事情。我不是说要你到处跳槽，也不是
saying oh I don't love this it's not my
说“哦，我不喜欢这个，这不是我的
passion no that probably means it's just
热情所在”，不，那可能只是意味着
work but if you're not making progress
工作而已。但是，如果你没有取得进展，
if you're not making money if you're not
赚不到钱，得不到
getting roles in films if you're not if
电影角色，
everything's just really hard really
一切都非常艰难，非常
hard you're in a position at that age to
艰难，那么在这个年纪，你可以
say you know what what I'm going to
说，你知道吗？我要
leave Milan and move to Munich or I'm
离开米兰，搬到慕尼黑，或者我
going to Dubai you have flexibility when
要去迪拜。你拥有很大的灵活性。
you're young you have Geographic
年轻人，你拥有地域上的
flexibility leaning to your advantage
灵活性，这正成为你的优势。
it's a heck of a lot easier right now to
现在
make money in Dubai than it is in
在迪拜赚钱比在
Caracus right you'd rather be good in a
加拉加斯容易得多，对吧？你宁愿在一个
great economy than outstanding in a
经济繁荣的地区做得好，也不愿在一个
mediocre economy you have Geographic
经济平庸的地区出类拔萃。你拥有地域上的
flexibility lean into your advantages
灵活性，要充分利用你的优势，
your flexibility your ability to recover
你的灵活性，你的恢复
your ability to Workshop what would you
能力，你的创新能力。如果
do for one of your Sons said to you how
你的儿子问你，
many sons have you got now I got two you
你现在有几个儿子？
got two sons that I know of that you
我知道你有两个儿子，你也
know of one of your sons comes to you
知道。其中一个儿子来找你
and says Dad I would like to be a I've
说：“爸爸，我想成为一名……我
read your book um all of your books and
读过你的书，嗯，你所有的书，
I think they're great but Dad I would
我觉得它们很棒，但是爸爸，我真的
love to be a professional actor and then
很想成为一名职业演员。”然后
your other son came to you and said I
你的另一个儿子来找你说：“我
want to be a musician I don't want to
想成为一名音乐家。”我不想
crush anybody's
打击任何人的
dreams uh a go for it I'll be supportive
梦想，嗯，去吧，我会支持你的。
um but this industry let's just look at
但是这个行业，我们来看看
the economics musician and acting has a
经济状况，音乐家和演员的
99% unemployment rate so you got to be
失业率高达99%，所以你必须成为那
in the 1% and I want you to set up
1%的人。我想请你设定一些
benchmarks for determining what it means
基准来衡量…… 成为
to be in the top 1% right 80 uh the most
顶尖1%意味着跻身全球最优秀的1%——没错，
talented actors in the world are in a
世界上80位最有才华的演员都加入了SAG-
union called sag Afra and by the way
Afra工会。顺便说一句，
it's not easy to get your union card you
获得工会会员卡可不容易，你
got to be in a Broadway play you got to
必须参演百老汇戏剧，必须获得
be recognized that's a big moment it's
认可——那是一个重要的时刻，就像
like getting your PGA golf tour card
获得PGA高尔夫巡回赛会员卡一样。拿到SAG会员卡
means you're one of the 180,000 most
意味着你是全球18万名最
talented creatives in the world last
有才华的创意人士之一。
year 83% of them didn't have health
去年，其中83%的人没有医疗
insurance because they didn't make more
保险，因为他们的收入不超过
$23,000 so you not only need to be in
2.3万美元。所以，你不仅需要跻身
the top 177% just to have health
前177%才能获得医疗
insurance you probably need to be in the
保险，实际上你可能需要跻身前
top 10% realistically the top 1% I know
10%，甚至前1%。我认识
a lot of working actors if I said this
很多演员，如果我说“这
is the guy from this show you'd be like
是某个节目里的那个人”，你可能会说“我的天哪，他太棒了，但
amazing he's not making a lot of money I
他收入不高”。我的
mean everybody talks about Tom Cruz the
意思是，每个人都在谈论汤姆·克鲁斯，但
majority of working actors you would say
大多数演员，你会说“
I know that woman I know that man
我认识那个女人，我认识那个男人，
they're great they make an okay living
他们都很优秀”。 他们现在的生活还算不错。
if they had achieve that level of
如果他们
excellence in almost any other industry
在其他任何行业达到同样的卓越水平，
they'd be they'd own a house and a
他们早就拥有自己的房子，甚至
second house in AA so if you want to be
在AA（可能是指某个行业或机构）也买房了。所以，如果你想成为
an athlete an actor a model an artist
运动员、演员、模特、艺术家、
open a restaurant open an iclub have a
开餐厅、开夜店、创立
jewelry line be a fashion designer I
珠宝品牌、成为时装设计师，我
don't want to crush anyone's dreams but
不想打击任何人的梦想，但
let's have a sober conversation that if
让我们冷静地谈谈。如果
you aren't getting bright green lights
你没有
1% really quickly and we put some guard
迅速获得认可，没有跻身顶尖1%的行列，我们就要设置一些限制条件。比如，
rails on it we're going to do this for 2
我们要做两
years 3 years can't pay your rent in two
三年，如果你两三年后付不起房租，你爸爸可能就不再帮
paying your rent at some point or maybe
你付房租了。或许
I'll continue to pay your rent but I
我会继续帮你付房租，但我
need you to start workshopping another
需要你开始考虑其他
career because here's the thing people
职业。因为
of young people oftentimes mistake their
年轻人常常把
hobbies for their passions and what I
爱好误认为是激情。我的
would suggest is and what I can
建议是，我可以向
guarantee you is being successful at
你保证，任何领域的成功都源于对某件事的精通，而激情则源于对
at something I'm renovating a house and
某件事的熟练掌握。比如，我正在装修房子，
there's this guy installing our soap
有个工人正在安装皂
stone who's the soapstone guy he's an
石。 那个做皂石的家伙是谁？他是个
Iraqi immigrant dropped out of high
伊拉克移民，高中辍学，但
school he knows everything about so
他对皂石了如指掌。
soapstone you can talk to you about the
你可以跟他聊
vein in the soapstone and which
皂石的纹理，以及
cories and he makes I've been very open
他制作的各种皂石。我对他很坦诚，也
with him I've talked about my book he
跟他聊过我的书。他
made 1.3 million pounds last year he's
去年赚了130万英镑，他就是那个做
the soapstone guy I can't imagine when
皂石的家伙。我简直无法想象
he was a kid he and I bonded over
他小时候的生活。我和他因为
football I would bet I don't know this I
足球而结缘。我敢打赌，我不知道，我
would bet he dreamt of being a football
敢打赌他梦想过成为足球
star and playing for a rock in the world
明星，在
cup at some point I doubt at the age of
世界杯上为某支球队效力。我怀疑他
17 he thought my I'm hoping in 15 years
17岁的时候会想：我希望15年后，
I'm installing soap stone and
我能为美国那些混蛋安装皂石，做
Renovations for American douchebags and
装修，还有
marab Bone I can't imagine that was his
马拉布·伯恩。我无法想象那是他的
dream right but here's the thing he has
梦想，对吧？但事实是，他现在的
an amazing life he takes care of his
生活很精彩。他照顾
kids he takes care of his parents he
孩子，赡养父母，
gets to take amazing vacations with his
还能和妻子一起享受美好的假期，
wife which makes him passionate about
这让他对
soapstone so yeah go be a fashion
皂石充满热情。所以，是的，你可以去当时装
designer but let's be honest if you're
设计师，但说实话，如果你连
not making enough money to pay your rent
房租都付不起，那就别想了。
within 2 years and you're not making
两年内
enough money to say form a family in 5
赚的钱不够组建家庭，五年后
years we're going to Workshop something
我们打算
else this requires such a mindset shift
另谋出路。这需要
in the current world because obviously
在这个时代彻底转变思维模式，因为很明显，如今的“
Vegas of validation is Instagram and Tik
验证”渠道是Instagram和
Tok now if I announce on Instagram that
TikTok。如果我在Instagram上宣布
I'm a tax lawyer for the next 10 years
未来十年我是一名税务律师（虽然我的Instagram账号并不算
not a great Instagram it's not going to
好），这并不会
increase my chance of getting laate
增加我找到伴侣的机会。
either but if I say that I am I don't
但如果我说我是……我不
know if I say that I'm part of football
知道，如果我说我是足球
club I'm in the you know the Junior
俱乐部的一员，比如在青年
Academy yeah or if I say that I'm
学院，或者如果我说我要
starting a business I'm probably going
创业，那么
to get laid more in the next 10 years
未来十年我可能会更容易找到伴侣。我
well the only push back I would get is
唯一可能遇到的阻力是，
that you have to be one of the 10 best
你必须是
soccer players in the world that year to
当年世界排名前十的足球运动员才能
play for Chelsea that is really hard
为切尔西效力，这真的很难，这
that is really that means you're the
意味着你必须是
best player in Sagal and then you go I
萨加尔最好的球员，然后你就会明白，
mean you just have to be Godlike
你必须天赋异禀，才能成为顶尖的
10% of tax lawyers that's tens of
10%的税务律师（成千上万的税务律师）坐
thousands of them fly private and get
私人飞机，享受着美好的性生活。
laid more than you think because they
比你想象的要多得多，因为他们坐
fly private and they can afford they can
私人飞机，他们负担得起，他们能
find someone and give them a wonderful
找到伴侣，给他们美好的
life so I mean look in a capitalist I'm
生活。我的意思是，看看资本主义，我
not saying this is how the world should
不是说世界就应该是这样，
be I'm saying this how the world
我是说世界就是这样。
is economic security provides you with
经济保障为你提供了
all sorts of opportunities for
各种各样的机会，让你体验各种经历，建立各种关系，创造
for romantic
浪漫的
opportunities and it is sexy to be great
机会。在任何领域都表现出色，
at anything and get Economic Security
并从中获得经济保障，这很吸引人。
from anything and I can't tell you I
我不能说我
love taking care of my kids because at
爱照顾我的孩子，因为
one point I was worried about my ability
我曾经担心自己是否有能力
to take care of my kids and not worry
照顾他们，而现在我不再为此担忧。
about it and this is where happiness
这就是幸福的来源。
comes from it's great to be in a
身处一个声望
Prestige industry and be a baller I get
卓著的行业，成为一个成功人士，这很棒。
reward from some of the fame I have
我现在的名气给我带来了一些回报，
right now I'm sure you get reward from
我相信你也从中受益。
it but the thing that is really
但
rewarding as you get older is I can lean
随着年龄的增长，真正让我感到满足的是，我可以全身心地投入到
into my relationships with my sons and I
与儿子的关系中，
don't have that economic fear I had the
不再像
first time my son came marching out of
第一次儿子从我
my girlfriend that is so rewarding I can
女朋友那里出来时那样担心经济问题。这真的很有意义。我可以
take care of my dad I don't have to
照顾我的父亲，我不用
worry about it my my dad's 90 going to
担心。我父亲已经90岁了，快
be 94 in a few weeks and he lives in a
94岁了。 几周后，他就住进了一栋
really nice home and he has a full-time
非常漂亮的房子，还有全职的
kind of health
护理人员。
million dollars a year to take care of
照顾我父亲每年大约需要25万美元，这是税后收入，
post tax there's no tax credit for it so
没有税收抵免，所以
it's about $400,000 in pre-tax income
税前收入大约是40万美元。
my sister who does really well but not
我妹妹收入也不错，但
as well as me we have a great
不如我。我们
partnership she handles it logistically
合作得很好，她负责后勤，我负责理财。能够
I handle the money and being able to do
做到这一点，
that and not have it be a source of
而且不会让它成为
stress in my life and know that my dad
我生活的压力来源，知道父亲的生活得到了
well okay it'd be great to be a football
很好的照顾，这感觉很棒。好吧，如果能成为一名足球
player trust me when you get to my age
运动员就太好了，相信我，当你到了我这个年纪，那种
that feels really good that feels really
感觉真的很棒，真的很好。
ends the means money is a means it's
金钱只是手段，它非常
really important it's hard to be happy
重要。在一个没有上限、经济压力巨大的社会里，很难感到快乐。
blood pressure of kids in low-income
低收入家庭的孩子的静息血压比中高收入家庭的
homes is higher than kids in middle and
孩子高，
upper M because they sense the anxiety
因为他们能感受到
for Mom and Dad I remember you know
父母的焦虑。我记得
losing my jacket when I was in the e8th
我八年级的时候丢了外套…… 本来会是
horrible day because I had to go home
糟糕的一天，因为我得回家
and tell my mom Jack is cost 33 bucks
告诉妈妈杰克花了33美元，这事儿一直
all in my head very
在我脑子里挥之不去，让我很
upsetting the ability to take care of
沮丧。能够照顾
your kids your parents do wonderful
孩子，父母为我做了很多美好的
things money affords you so many
事情，金钱能给你带来很多
wonderful things that getting to a
美好的事物，达到
certain level of Economic Security is
一定的经济安全水平只是
the means but the ends the reason you
手段，但最终目的并非如此。你之所以能获得
get to Economic Securities is so you can
经济安全，是为了让你摆脱
free up and be free of anxiety and have
焦虑，拥有
some additional time so you can focus on
更多的时间，从而专注于真正重要的事——建立
the ends and the ends is deep and
深刻而
meaningful relationships I spend the
有意义的人际关系。我把
majority of my money on travel and
大部分钱都花在旅行和
experiences with my family and friends I
与家人朋友的相处上。我花钱如
spend a [__] ton of money and I
流水，但我乐在其中。
hoard money once I hit my number
一旦达到目标，就没必要囤积金钱。
I hit my number seven years ago and I
七年前我达到了目标，
started thinking I could be a
开始幻想自己能成为
billionaire what was your number uh my
亿万富翁。你的目标是多少？嗯，我的目标是1亿美元。
number was 100 million by the way my
顺便说一下，我大学毕业时的目标是100万美元，到了30多岁的时候，
million and then by my 30s I thought
我想，
well if I had 10 million I'm done and
如果我有1000万美元，我就心满意足了。但后来
then things got so expensive and my
生活成本越来越高，我的
greed glance kept going and my number
贪婪之心也越来越强烈，最终我的目标变成了
was 100 million why have a number why
1亿美元。为什么要设定一个目标呢？
did why do people listening need to
为什么人们需要
create a number what's the value of
设定一个数字？设定这样一个“底线”有什么价值？
well you need a goal and you need to be
你需要一个目标，并且需要
thoughtful about how much money you're
认真思考你需要多少钱。
going to need so if you figure out I'm
比如，如果你算出来，
going to need a I'm going to need 80,000
我需要每年8万美元来
a year to live the definition of rich is
维持生活，那么富有的定义就是
having a ton of [__] and impress your
拥有很多东西来炫耀，而
friends the definition of wealth is
财富的定义是
knowing that the passive income that you
知道你从
would get from growth from your stocks
股票增长、股息、
or dividends or incomes or rental income
收入或租金收入中获得的被动收入
is greater than your burn so you work
大于你的支出。所以你工作是出于自愿，而
work because you want to not because you
不是因为
need to that's the definition of wealth
需要。这就是财富的定义。设定
so having a number is just backward
一个数字只是反向积分。好吧，
okay um I want to have at least $3
我想每年至少有300万美元来过
million a year to live the life I want
我想要的
to live all right assuming a 4% return
生活。假设4%的回报率，
that means I need $75 million so I
这意味着我需要7500万美元，所以我向上
rounded up to 100 million right I got
取整到1亿美元。顺便说一下，我运气
exceptionally lucky to get there by the
非常好才达到这个目标。你
way see above in 2008 I was broke I was
看上面，2008年我一贫如洗，当时我才10
broke at the age of 4243 that did not
岁。  4243，
feel good I got very lucky started a
感觉不太好。我运气很好，创办了一家
company bull market the last 16 years
公司，正值牛市，过去16年都是如此，真是
lucky but you should be able you should
天时地利人和。但你应该也能做到，你应该
have a number you should say this is the
有一个目标，你应该说这是
amount of money I need and once I get to
我需要的钱，一旦达到
this number enjoy it and start giving it
这个目标，就好好享受，然后开始捐赠
away we we really need to because I'm
出去。我们真的需要这样做，因为我
thinking
思考
about this conversation through is like
这次谈话的角度，就像我
different stages in my own journey and
自己人生旅程的不同阶段，以及在
you at different steps in my journey and
不同的阶段我希望从你那里得到的建议。
I I just flashed back to working in
我突然想起了在
those call centers where I was making
呼叫中心工作的日子，那时我
just about enough money to well to be
挣的钱勉强够用。说实话，
fair if I'm being completely honest I
我的确
did have disposable income but when I
有可支配收入，但当我
was poor I was Reckless with my money
穷的时候，我花钱很随意。嗯，
mhm so I would get the £500 disposable
所以我会在发薪日拿到500英镑的可支配
income on payday leave the call center
收入，然后离开呼叫中心，
go and buy a 400 TV flat screen TV and
去买一台400英镑的平板电视，
put it in a room where the TV was as big
把它放在一个房间里，电视机几乎占满了整个
as the wall of my room all right and I'm
房间的墙。好吧，我正在
trying to I'm really trying to zoom in
努力，我真的在努力关注那些离
nine figures yeah and they're like okay
九位数还很远的人。是的。 他们就像在说，好吧，
Scott I want to be Scott Galloway so
斯科特，我想成为斯科特·加洛韦，那么我需要
what is the set of steps or the mindset
哪些步骤、心态，或者说，
the fishing rod I need in my mind become
我需要什么样的“钓竿”才能成为年入
Scott Galloway nine figures well the
九位数的斯科特·加洛韦呢？
first is the first is some of it is luck
首先，有些成功是运气。再说一遍，
a again a lot of my successes if I'd
我的很多成功都离不开运气。如果我
been born in Europe I don't think I'd
出生在欧洲，我想我不会
have that number Europe's not as
有这么高的成就。欧洲对失败的
forgiving of entrepreneurs that have
企业家并不宽容。
failed I've had a lot of failure if I
我经历过很多失败。如果我
lived in China I think there's a decent
生活在中国，我想
chance I'd be in jail so the smart again
我很有可能已经在监狱里了。所以，聪明才是关键。
the smartest thing I've ever done was
我做过的最明智的事情就是
being born in California so you saying
出生在加利福尼亚。你说
to move does that matter what's that
要搬家，这重要吗？那是什么意思？
should I move City oh if you're young
我应该搬到哪个城市吗？哦，如果你年轻，
the first thing you want to do is to get
你首先想做的就是去
to one of 20 super cities if you're I'm
20个超级城市之一。如果你——我
just talking about someone who wants to
只是在说一个想
be an economic analy
成为经济分析师的人——对吧？有些人
right you might who doesn't okay but
可能不想。好吧，但
some people might say Scott it's your
有些人可能会说，斯科特，你的
way it's not the right way I want to
方式不对。我想
teach coach football in my little
在我的小村庄里当足球教练，
village outside in the Amalfi Coast I
在阿马尔菲海岸边，我
can make 55,000 working running a small
可以赚钱。 年薪5.5万美元，经营一家小
bakery and have a really nice life I
面包店，过着非常美好的生活。我
think they would have clicked more power
想他们会更支持
to you that's not the majority of the
你，为你点赞。但这并非我身边大多数
people I hang out with majority of the
人的现状。我接触的大多数
young people I hear from realize that
年轻人都意识到，
and love in a capitalist society and
在资本主义社会，财富等同于价值和爱，
they want to be economically very secure
他们渴望经济上的安全感。最简单也
the easiest thing the best piece of
最好的
advice is one get credentialed we live
建议就是：获得资格认证。我们生活
in a LinkedIn economy what you did your
在一个LinkedIn盛行的时代，你的
success is especially impressive because
成功尤其令人印象深刻，因为
on average people who get a college
平均而言，拥有大学
degree earn 50 to 100% more over the
学位的人一生收入会高出50%到100%。
course of their life there's an entire
有很多
set of industries that are off limits to
行业对
people that don't have credentialing I
没有资格认证的人是封闭的。我曾在
worked to work for Morgan Stanley we not
摩根士丹利工作，我们
only didn't hire people without college
不仅不雇用没有大学
degrees we didn't hire people that
学位的人，也不雇用
didn't go to one of eight universities
没有毕业于八所指定大学之一的人。
Stanley at that time so if you can get
当时，要想在摩根士丹利找到工作，你不仅需要上大学，还需要毕业于这八所大学之一。所以，如果你能获得
credentialing the second thing not
资格认证，那就太好了。第二点，并非
everyone's cut out for college I get
每个人都适合上大学。 我明白
that the second thing is get to a super
第二点，那就是要尽快进入超级
City two-thirds of all economic growth
城市。
over the next 30 Years is going to take
未来30年三分之二的经济增长将
place in one of 20 cities so if you're
发生在20个城市之一。所以，如果你
in that small town in Italy you want to
在意大利的小镇，你会想
get to Milan as quickly as possible and
尽快去米兰，
then if you can you want to get to
然后如果可以的话，你会想
London as quickly as possible or Munich
尽快去伦敦、慕尼黑
or a bigger city and then quite frankly
或其他更大的城市。坦白说，
if you have total Geographic agility and
如果你拥有完全的地理位置
flexibility ignoring the ridiculous ins
灵活性，忽略美国那些荒谬的政策，
of the US you want to get to New York or
你会想去纽约或
San Francisco because to be good in San
旧金山，因为在
Francisco is much better than being
旧金山做得好远比在斯图加特做得出色要好得多。
economic here's the thing I'm I'm a
经济……是这样的，我只是个
mediocre I'm a mediocre Surfer I've
普通的冲浪者，我甚至已经放弃了。
actually even given it up but when I was
但当我
young and I used to go to Hawaii and the
年轻的时候，我经常去夏威夷，那里的
waves were perfect perfect I started
海浪完美无瑕，我开始
believing I was a good Surfer where I go
觉得自己是个不错的冲浪者。就像我去
to Aspen after a Fresh coat of snow and
阿斯彭，刚下过一场新雪，
I'm like I'm a decent skier no you're
我就觉得自己是个不错的滑雪者一样。不，你
not the snow and the waves are [__]
不是，雪和海浪
amazing anyone could be a good skier in
太棒了，任何人都可以成为…… 在
this [__] get to where the waves in the
这破地方，滑雪高手才能找到
snow are amazing and that's generally
雪浪最壮观的地方，这通常
speaking in cities and when you're young
指的是城市。年轻的时候，
you can be in a city because you can
你可以住在城市里，因为你可以
live in a 400 foot apartment you can be
住在400平方英尺的公寓里，可以整天在
out of the house all day you can dance
外面玩，可以一边跳舞一边
Between The Raindrops and make money but
赚钱。但是，
when you are in a city you know how when
当你身处城市，就像
you play tennis if you play with someone
打网球一样，如果你和比
much better than you it elevates your
你水平高得多的人一起打球，你的水平也会提升。在城市里，你
playing against Serena Williams every
每天都在和塞雷娜·威廉姆斯这样的高手较量，
day everyone is smart everyone is well
每个人都很聪明，每个人都
dressed everyone is working hard
衣着光鲜，每个人都在努力工作，
everyone is Taking Chances and you are
每个人都在抓住机会。你
surrounded by people who are very
身边都是
successful and you are going to bump off
成功人士，你会每天都错失
professional and personal opportunity
职业和个人发展的机会。趁年轻，一定要抓住这些机会，
because when you start collecting dogs
因为当你像
and kids as I did in my 30s I could no
我一样，到了30多岁，开始养狗生子的时候，我就
longer afford to stay in New York so so
负担不起纽约的生活了，所以
I had to move to Delray Beach in Florida
我不得不搬到佛罗里达州的德雷海滩。我
when I say have to we have a wonderful
说“不得不”，是因为我们在
life down there there's not a fraction
那里的生活很美好。但
for someone in their 20s and 30s now I
对于20多岁和30多岁的人来说，德雷海滩的机会远不及纽约。我当时
already had professional momentum but
已经有了事业上的起色，但是……
Sunday to Thursday night I was commuting
周四晚上我通勤
to New York because that's where the
去纽约，因为那里是
action was so one credentialing but two
活动中心，所以一方面要办证，另一方面
absolutely get to one of 20 super cities
一定要去那20个超级城市之一。
when you say 20 super cities I thinking
说到20个超级城市，我想，
now we're having this conversation in a
我们现在讨论的这个话题，
world where AI seems to be the biggest
人工智能似乎是当今世界最热门的
topic of conversation it seems to be
话题，它似乎正在
ripping up many Industries but it I also
颠覆许多行业。但我也在
reflect on that I go where is the AI
思考，人工智能究竟在哪里？
opportunity going to be if that is the
如果这是
biggest wave coming into Shore in terms
肖尔地区即将迎来的最大机遇，那么
of opportunity um should I be playing my
我是否应该
based on artificial intelligence because
基于人工智能进行地理决策呢？因为
everyone's raving about how big of an
每个人都在热议人工智能带来的巨大
opportunity that is and Technology
机遇，而且
generally over the next 10 years seems
未来十年科技似乎真的会
like it's really going to eat up a lot
席卷很多
of uh industry yeah I don't I don't know
行业。是的，我不知道
if it' be possible to determine
是否可以根据
geography based on AI what I would say
人工智能来确定地理位置。我想说的是，
is okay you know every literally a to my
你知道，我纽约大学的同学们
Francisco the day they graduate there's
毕业那天都会坐飞机去旧金山，而就在
just within a s mile radius of San
旧金山国际机场方圆一英里内，过去六个月
been more wealth created I think in the
创造的财富比
last six months than than Germany's
德国
created in the last decade Nvidia is
过去十年创造的财富还要多。英伟达的
worth more than the entire UK stock
市值超过了整个英国
market nvidia's they make the they're
股市。英伟达制造
artificial intelligence they make a GPU
人工智能的大脑，他们制造的GPU本质上
which is essentially a microchip that
是一种微芯片，为
powers all AI right now and no one can
所有人工智能提供动力，而且现在没人能
buy them fast enough now they have
抢到。他们有
30,000 people I would bet 10 or 15,000
3万名员工，我敢打赌10 或者说，
of them are worth at least $10 million
其中15000人现在至少价值1000万美元，
now because the 30,000 employees got
因为30000名员工都获得了
stock options and when a company goes
股票期权。当一家公司的市值
from from 300 billion to 3 trillion it
从3000亿美元增长到3万亿美元时，
means everyone is getting rich that
意味着每个人都会变得富有。这种情况
doesn't happen that often in Dortmund it
在多特蒙德
doesn't happen that often it doesn't
并不常见，真的不
happen I mean kind right you grow up in
常见。我的意思是，如果你在英国长大，
engl do you either go to work for Audi
你会去奥迪工作吗？
nothing wrong with that make a good
这没什么不好，也能过上不错的
living but if you're young and you think
生活。但如果你年轻，想
I really want to get in front of the
真正抓住机遇，
biggest waves you want to go to one of
你会去
several cities you want to have the
几个城市中的一个，你会想
winds at your back so if you're young
顺风顺水。所以，如果你年轻，你
what do you have you have agility
拥有什么？你拥有
geographically but going back you
地理上的灵活性。但回到你
initially asked me what's the algorithm
最初问我的算法是什么，
what are the steps and I tried to the
步骤是什么，我尝试参考了《
book's called the algebra wealth I tried
财富代数》这本书，试图将
to distill it down to a a small number
其提炼成几个关键
of of features the first is focus go all
特征。首先是专注。
in on something once you find you work
一旦你在20多岁的时候找到自己擅长的领域，就全力以赴。
shop in your 20s once you find something
一旦你找到
you're really good at that you could be
自己真正擅长的领域，你就有可能
in the top 1% at and here's the key part
跻身前1%。 关键在于，
as we referenced before that has a 90
正如我们之前提到的，
plus perc employment rate and 90% of
就业率超过90%的行业，90%的
Industries have that but if you can be
行业都达到了这个水平。如果你能
in the top 10% of an industry that has a
跻身就业率超过90%的行业前10%，
90 plus perc employment rate you're
你就能
going to make really good money first
赚到非常可观的收入。
thing Focus try not to have side hustles
首先，要专注于主业，尽量不要有副业。
if you have a side hustle it means your
如果你有副业，那就意味着你的
main hustle isn't working use side
主业发展得不好。你可以利用副业
hustle to Workshop new main hustles but
来磨练新主业的技能，但
once you find something you're really
一旦你找到自己真正
good at go all in on it can I pause
擅长的领域，就要全力以赴。在
there just as we keep going cuz I want
我们继续之前，我可以先暂停一下吗？因为我想
to just provide counter arguments just
提供一些反驳论点，以防有人在
their own minds I I think about me in
心里反对。我想起了我在
the southwest of England as I grew up
英格兰西南部长大的经历，
and I was in pouth working at a
我曾经在一家
MacDonald's I worked there for two days
麦当劳工作过两天，
but I worked in retail and shops and
但我也做过零售店之
stuff what I had at that moment I in
类的工作。现在
hindsight was a void of information so
回想起来，当时我对这方面的信息非常匮乏，所以
I could only work at like a clothing
我只能在
store and a McDonald's because I didn't
服装店和麦当劳之类的地方工作。 我
have any other information and if a kid
没有其他信息，如果一个孩子
hasn't gone to University or similar
没上过大学或者类似的
things just haven't hasn't got the
地方，他们就不知道这些
information and they've stumbled across
信息，然后偶然发现了
across this podcast but they're working
这个播客，但他们却在类似
Wendy's or Burger King for example and
温蒂汉堡或汉堡王之类的快餐店工作，他们就会
they just like how do I get out of this
想：我该怎么离开
Burger King
汉堡王？
Scott I'm a cashier at Burger King yeah
斯科特，我在汉堡王当收银员。是的，听着，我……
look I I don't I I I want to be
我想说
clear I think there is a certain
清楚，我认为“
downside to the notion that we live in a
我们生活在一个
meritocracy and it creates a lot of rage
精英社会”这种观念存在一定的弊端，它会
and shame among young people and that is
在年轻人中引发很多愤怒和羞耻感。这种
the notion that in America especially
观念认为，尤其是在美国，
anyone can be anything well not really
任何人都可以成为任何想成为的人——好吧，其实不然。
boss because the problem with thinking
因为认为
we live in a meritocracy is that if you
我们生活在一个精英社会的问题在于，如果你
don't make it you [__] up it's your
没成功，那就是你搞砸了，都是你的
fault yeah and there's dignity in every
错。是的，每份
work what I would say to someone working
工作都有尊严。我想对那些
in a Burger King or in fast food that
在汉堡王或快餐店工作，但
want something bigger work really I was
想要更好的工作的人说：我曾经是
on the board of Panera Bread which is a
Panera Bread的董事会成员，Panera Bread是一家
fast food chain or Quick Service they
快餐连锁店，或者叫快速服务（Quick Service），他们
call it qsr they like the term someone
称之为QSR。他们喜欢…… 把那些
who was hardworking and showed up at
勤奋努力、
work every day on time and worked with
每天准时上班、与
their colleagues and acted like they own
同事合作、并且像老板一样对待工作的人称为“老板”，他们
the place probably within two years
可能两年内
could be managing the place and making
就能成为经理，年收入达到
60 or 80 grand a year now I'm not
六七万。我不是
suggesting you go all in on food but
建议你把所有精力都投入到餐饮业，但
there's always dignity in work there's
工作总是有尊严的，
always opportunity for people who work
对于那些
hard and act like owners and are good
努力工作、像老板一样对待工作、为人友善、乐于
people and try and look out for other
助人、
people and are good
并且是优秀
managers that might just be for you a
管理者的人来说，机会总是存在的。对你来说，这可能只是实现目标的手段，
means to an end where you're working
你一边工作一边
work shopping other stuff to say how do
思考其他事情，比如如何去
I get to to school how do I get to
上学、如何去参加
training how do I find a better job how
培训、如何找到更好的工作、如何
do I save for a one-year apprenticeship
攒钱参加为期一年的电工学徒
program to become an electrician how do
计划、如何
I start meeting people you got to pay
开始结识人脉等等。你得支付各种
your bills there's dignity in all work I
账单。所有工作都有尊严。我
coach a lot of young men and the first
指导过很多年轻人，我跟他们
thing I say is you got to start making
说的第一件事就是，你得开始
some money and they're like I'm not
赚钱。他们会说，我不想去
going to work at CVS or at McDonald's
CVS或者麦当劳工作。我会说，
I'm like yeah you are because you need a
不，你必须去，因为你需要体验一下
taste for flesh the best way to make a
赚钱的感觉，这是赚很多钱的最好方法。
lot of money is to start making a little
赚钱的目的是先赚点
bit of money but have a plan I want to
钱，但要有个计划。我想
be the assistant manager of this
成为这家麦当劳的助理经理，
McDonald's I want to save enough money
我想攒够钱
so I can go back to school I want to
重返校园，我想
save enough money so I can move to Dubai
攒够钱搬到迪拜
or move to London and get a job there
或伦敦，在那里找一份
that might be higher paying is there
薪水更高的工作。
anything about the CVS or the Burger
关于CVS、汉堡
King or the whatever that I should be
王或其他类似的公司，我应该
looking at to check that it has room for
注意些什么，看看它们是否有发展空间？
you know if we're starting by making a
如果我们从赚点钱开始，有没有哪些地方适合赚点
place to make a little bit of money
钱，哪些地方不适合？
of money well growth sort of solves
增长可以
solve problems so if you're working at a
解决很多问题。比如，如果你在
Chipotle Doug McMillan who's the CEO of
Chipotle工作，沃尔玛的CEO道格·麦克米兰最初是从装卸
Walmart started uh loading trucks he
货车开始的，他在装卸
worked in the Loading Docks but he was
码头工作，但他当时也在
also working for the retailer That Grew
为这家零售商工作，而沃尔玛的增长速度超过了
faster than any retailer in history so
历史上任何一家零售商。所以
is your company
你的公司在
growing uh first thing growth kind of
增长吗？首先，增长可以
solves all problems right if you were
解决所有问题，对吧？如果你
mediocre at Google you did a lot better
在谷歌表现平平，你的表现也
than if you were great at General Motors
比你很优秀要好得多。 通用汽车
the last 20 years because one was
过去20年的发展情况，是因为一家公司在
growing one wasn't so so is it growing
增长，另一家公司没有增长，所以现在的情况是增长还是停滞不前？这更多
learning right am I getting skills that
取决于具体情况。我身边是否有人真心希望我成功？比如这家店的经理，他会像我一样鼓励我，说“继续努力，我会帮你找到街对面那家店的助理经理职位”。我是否在正确地学习？我是否在获得具
challenge me is this a little bit hard
有挑战性的技能？这有点难？没关系。
that's okay is it stressful that's okay
这有压力？也没关系。如果
too you don't want stress go be a
你不想承受压力，那就去当
security guarden a parking lot no stress
停车场保安吧。没有压力，就没有回报。
no upside the market is really good at
市场很擅长权衡
trading off the more stressful and tense
压力和紧张程度，
and like God I can't keep up here that
以及那种“天哪，我跟不上节奏了”的感觉。这
probably means you're learning that
可能意味着你在学习，也可能意味着
probably means you're going to make more
你会赚更多
money so am I learning do I have senior
钱。那么，我是否在学习？我是否有高层领导的
level sponsorship am I in a company
支持？我所在的公司是否在
that's growing am I in a city where
发展？我所在的城市是否充满
there's economic Vitality do I have flow
活力？我是否拥有源源不断的
flow of interesting people flow of
有趣人脉？我是否有源源不断的
interesting friends that I might start
有趣朋友，可以和我一起
another business with flow of potential
创业？我是否有源源不断的潜在人才？
one and three relationships begin at
人际关系始于
work and every hr's hair is on HR
工作，而且每时每刻都让人焦头烂额。人力资源
manager hair is on fire right now one
经理现在肯定也焦头烂额。
talk about that a third of all
三分之一的恋情始于职场，我们常说，三分之一的
relationships begin at work and 99% of
恋情都始于职场，其中99%都是
them are consensual right young people
双方自愿的。年轻人
have to find a place to to find other
需要找到结识新
mates if you will but there's a ser and
朋友的地方，但
then more importantly I think than all
更重要的是，我认为你需要
of this is assembling a kitchen cabinet
组建一个“智囊团”，
of people that will you can be really
成员之间可以坦诚相待。比如，你可以说：“
honest with I'm working at Burger King I
我在汉堡王工作，我
think I'm doing pretty well there they
觉得我做得还不错。他们
want to make me managers at In-N-Out
想让我去In-N-Out
Burger make about 110 $120,000 a year in
汉堡当经理，在美国，经理的年收入大约在11万到12万美元之间，
in the US and they're even given a
甚至还有
chance to participate in profit sharing
机会参与利润分成。
and I'm not suggesting being fast food
我并不是建议你一辈子都待在快餐店，
the rest of your life but have a plan
但你需要制定一个计划。”
and then you got to have a kitchen
然后，你需要组建一个“
cabinet put together a group of three
智囊团”，由三
four people who know you who you trust
四个了解你、你信任的人组成，
you and you can be totally transparent
你可以完全坦诚地告诉他们：“我
this how much money I'm making these are
赚多少钱？我有哪些
my opportunities these are this is what
机会？我
I'm good at what I'm not good at what do
擅长什么？我不擅长什么？
you think I should do and who are those
你们觉得我应该做什么？”这些人是谁？
people in terms of are they people that
他们是比
are ahead of you in in the race of life
你更有经验的人吗？ 在人生这场竞赛中，
or are they first off don't approach
首先，不要贸然接近
someone and say I I find you I want you
别人说“我找到你了，我想让你
to be my mentor right cuz that's a high
做我的导师”，因为这要求太高了，
bar and a lot of people are really busy
而且很多人都很忙。你应该说“
it's like hey uh I I'm I think you're
嘿，呃，我觉得你很了不起”，或者“你是一位成功人士，
who's made it doesn't have to be a
不一定是
baller but someone who's living a
大人物，但至少是一位
virtuous life who seems smart and nice
品德高尚、看起来聪明友善的人，
to you can I get some advice from you
我可以向你请教一些问题吗？我可以问你一些
questions can we do a call can we have a
问题吗？我们可以通个电话吗？我们可以一起喝杯
coffee there are a lot of people out
咖啡吗？”。有很多
there who want to help younger people
愿意帮助年轻人的人，
and take it as a compliment can I get
把这当作一种赞美。“我可以向你请教一些问题吗？”向
your advice ask them for advice don't
他们寻求建议。不要在没有
make big decisions without talking to
和别人商量的情况下做出重大决定。就像
the label from inside of the bottle
瓶子里的标签很难看清真相一样，真的很难。多和别人交流，
save save yourself from yourself so that
保护自己，避免陷入困境。比如，如果
you're a young woman working at a Burger
你是一位在汉堡王工作的年轻女性，
King and you hopefully you meet some
你希望能够遇到一些
people and say hey can I just get some
人，然后说“嘿，我可以向你
advice for and by the way it might be
请教一些问题吗？”顺便说一句，对方也可能是
someone else working at Burger King like
其他在汉堡王工作的人。 就像汉堡王那样，
this person has a act together this this
这个人做事很有条理，这个
person just has her acting she's just
人演技精湛，她只是很
smart we all know those people we meet
聪明。我们都认识这样的人，我们遇到过
them and we work with them like you know
他们，和他们一起工作过，你知道，
this person just kind of Switched on
这个人就像突然开窍了一样，
they just seem to have better judgment
他们在
around certain issues so what I would
某些问题上似乎更有判断力。所以我
say is have a plan don't be afraid to
想说的是，要制定计划，不要害怕
make changes put together a kitchen
做出改变，组建一个核心
cabinet realize there's dignity in all
团队，要意识到所有
work and any company even something
工作和任何公司都有尊严，即使是像
you'd see as low brow like fast food
快餐店这样你认为低端的公司，
those organizations need talented people
这些机构也需要有才能的人
to go up the ranks and make money
晋升并赚钱，
because the turnover is enormous so I
因为人员流动非常大。所以我认为
dignity in any work you said something
任何工作都有机会和尊严。你刚才说了一件
really interesting which I I don't think
非常有趣的事情，
I've ever had anybody talk about before
我以前从未听人提起过，
which is you said don't ask someone to
你说不要主动要求别人
be your mentor and I Frank I get asked
做你的导师。弗兰克，我每周都会被好
to be someone's Mentor several times a
几次邀请做别人的导师，
week as I'm sure you do yeah and I've
我相信你也是。是的，我从来
never given people advice on why that
没有建议过别人为什么这
isn't the right right approach but you
不是正确的方法，但你
said there that you don't think that's
刚才说你认为这不是
the right approach so I wanted to just
正确的方法，所以我想
pause and ask you why well you don't go
停下来问问你为什么。你不会主动去
up to a strange person and say do you
接近一个陌生人。 如果有人问你
want to have sex you go up and say do
想不想发生性关系，你可以走上前去问他/她
you want to have and do you want to have
你想不想……你想不想聊聊天？你想不想再喝
another drink do you want to grab coffee
一杯？你想不想一起喝咖啡？
do you want to go to the
你想不想去看
movies can I ask you a question can I
电影？我可以问你个问题吗？我可以向你请教
get some advice from you you ease into
一些建议吗？你要循序渐进地建立
the relationship because to ask someone
关系，因为直接问别人“你愿意做
to be your Mentor is just very
我的导师吗？”会让人感到非常
intimidating the person has to go do I
紧张。对方会想：我真的愿意在
month for the next five years and then
接下来的五年里每个月都和这个人见面，然后
break up with them if it you know if I'm
如果觉得不开心就和他/她分手吗？
not enjoying this relationship so you
所以你
don't need to say will you be my mentor
不需要问“你愿意做我的导师吗？”，这听起来太正式了。你可以直接说：“我可以就某些事情向你
your advice on something I really
请教吗？我非常
respect you I think you're so smart
尊重你，我觉得你在这方面很聪明。我
issues in my life some questions I'd
生活中遇到了一些问题，有些疑问，
love to just just get your advice can we
很想听听你的建议。我们可以一起
grab coffee or can we do a five or
喝杯咖啡吗？或者我们可以打个五到
10-minute call if someone emails me and
十分钟的电话吗？”如果有人给我发邮件
says I'm thinking I get a lot I'm
说：“我在思考……”我经常收到这样的邮件：“我在
thinking about starting a business I'm
考虑创业，我在
thinking about going to business school
考虑读商学院，
can I get some time I try to say yes and
我可以抽出点时间吗？”我会尽量答应。
call with you if someone asks me to be
如果有人请我做他们的导师，我可以和你进行15分钟的Zoom通话。但我真的没时间，
don't have time to you know I can barely
你知道，我
Mentor me right now the I just don't
现在连指导自己都困难，根本没
have time to commit to being someone's
时间专门去指导别人。
Mentor but if someone emails me and says
但如果有人发邮件给我，说
I need advice around the specific issue
他们需要一些关于特定问题的建议，
and then what happens
然后会发生什么呢？
you hear that they're you they're raised
你听说他们和
by a single mother like me they're a
我一样，都是单亲妈妈抚养长大的，他们人
good person they're struggling their
很好，但他们现在很挣扎，他们的
sister's got an eating disorder and
妹妹患有饮食障碍，
they're struggling with it and they're
他们正在努力克服，他们正在
trying to they're thinking about
考虑
starting a business and you're like oh
创业。你会说，哦不不，别
no no don't do that right now you've got
现在这么做，你有
a good job like you just make some you
一份不错的工作，你只需要
just help them with some common sense
帮他们做一些常识性的
decisions common
决定，一些常识性的事情。
sense and then what happens you become
然后会发生什么呢？你会
emotionally invested in their success
不由自主地投入到他们的成功中，
and then they email you a month later
一个月后他们给你发邮件，你会问，
and you're like what's going on and you
怎么回事？你
want to do another call you know ease
想再通话一次，你知道，循序渐进比较好。
into it so anyways I think it's much
所以，我觉得直接向
easier to just ask someone for help and
别人寻求帮助和建议要容易得多。
people out there you doesn't have to be
外面有很多聪明人，你不必像斯蒂芬·
a baller like step Bartlett there's a
巴特利特那样成为篮球明星，他们
lot of smart people out there that can
可以
give you good advice because I think
给你很好的建议，因为我认为
this is really important I I don't think
这真的很重要。正如我
I've as I said I don't think I've had
所说，我好像还没听
anyone talk about this but you get a lot
人谈过这个，但你会收到很多
messages have you been able to figure
信息。你有没有
out exactly why some of them perk your
弄明白为什么有些信息
interest so much so that you'd give them
如此吸引你，以至于你会花
15 minutes on a zoom call is is there is
15分钟和他们进行Zoom通话？是不是有什么
there a sort of a psychological formula
心理规律能打动
that gets to you well the first is okay
你？首先，简洁性很重要。如果信息很长，像
you know a novel I'm just not going to
小说那么长，我肯定看不完。
get through it uh obviously and this is
这一点
hard to control but they reference
很难控制，但他们会提到
someone you know or they they make a
你认识的人，或者建立
connection we're both graduates of
联系——比如我们都是
Berkeley or I met you I came up to you
伯克利的毕业生，或者我在校园里见过你，我上前跟
and said hi to you at can or we have a
你打招呼，或者我们有
mutual friend or I too was raised by a
共同的朋友，或者我也是
single they make some sort of personal
单亲家庭长大的。他们会建立某种个人
connection and they make the ass very
联系，而且他们的信息非常
crisply I'm writing because I'd love
简洁明了。我写这篇文章是因为我喜欢……
some advice around this I'm writing
关于这件事，我有一些建议。我写这封信是
because I'd like an introduction I'm
因为我想先做个自我介绍，
writing because I'm applying for your
因为我正在申请贵公司
position for managing editor for prop
道具媒体执行编辑的职位。所以，请直奔主题，说明你的
the ask and try and make some sort of
要求，并尝试建立一些
personal connection and the other thing
个人联系。另外，
I would say although I hate you know I
虽然我不太喜欢这种做法，但我还是想说，一定要
persistent because a lot of times I get
坚持不懈。因为很多时候，我收到
an email I think it's a good kid I
一封邮件，觉得对方很不错，
should really set up a call or something
应该安排个电话之类的，
and then I go on to the next 85 emails I
然后我又继续查看接下来的85封邮件，甚至都
have and I don't even remember getting
记不起收到过
that email so I would say don't be
这封邮件。所以我的建议是，不要害怕
afraid to hit again and just say hey
再次联系，
just putting at the top of your inbox
只需在邮件开头写上“嘿，我知道
know you're busy if I can grab 10
你很忙，如果你能抽出10
minutes your time I'd be really
分钟时间，我将不胜感激”。
discouraged if they don't get back to
如果他们没有回复你，也不要气馁，这不代表你做得
it off that's okay don't worry about it
不好，继续联系下一位，不要轻易放弃，没关系，别担心，别担心。
unbelievably profound because I if I
我有个想法，如果你和孩子们——你认识的孩子们，我未来的孩子们——谈谈如何在生活中提出要求，这对他们的长远发展轨迹的影响是难以置信的深远。因为
think back through my life when I was 18
回想我的人生，从18
years old stealing those pizzas in
岁在曼彻斯特偷披萨，到我人生道路上的
Manchester or every step along the way
每一步，我人生
trajectory were sending an email yeah
轨迹中的一些重要转折点都是发邮件。是的，没错，
and yeah pretty like yeah pretty much
几乎
all of them started with sending an
所有的转折点都是从发
email but we don't teach people how to
邮件开始的。但是我们并没有教人们如何
send an email and you're you're on the
发邮件，而你
every month or whatever so you can see
每个月都会收到成千上万封邮件，所以你可以
bad and good from a bird's eye view and
从宏观的角度看到邮件的好坏。
the things you've just said there I
你刚才说的那些，我
completely agree with the the size of
完全同意。
the the message um being specific in the
邮件的篇幅很重要，
askk as you said um playing to Ego in
就像你说的，在提问时要具体明确，还要以
some way letting them know that you've
某种方式迎合他们的自尊心，让他们知道你
read something you've done or you're
读过他们的作品，你做过他们的事情，或者你对
interested in them or you know someone
他们感兴趣，或者你认识某个人。
all those things has such a big such a
所有这些都会产生
big impact I think if you think about
巨大的影响。我想，如果你想想
your life and you go okay I'm going to
自己的人生，然后…… 好吧，我要
live for I'm going to live a hundred
活到一
years and I'm probably going to ask for
百岁，我可能会提出
things 10,000 times if I can increase my
一万次请求。如果我能把
success rate of those asks by
这些请求的成功率提高
10% because I'm just more thoughtful in
10%，因为我会更认真地思考
how I ask for things my life could end
如何提出请求，我的人生最终可能会走向
up in a completely different place mhm
完全不同的方向。嗯，有点像
kind of like what you said about you
你说的，你
only need a couple of wins to really be
只需要几次成功就能真正获得
successful in life you only need if you
成功。如果你
send 10 10 emails you only need like one
发了10封邮件，只需要一个
person to say yes I'll invest and and be
人说“好的，我会投资”，然后你就可以
willing to endure the rejection of the
承受其他
nine I had a kid this young kid come up
九次的拒绝。我之前遇到过一个小孩，一个很年轻的小孩，他走过来问我：“
to me I was just in can I'm a big fan
我是你的超级粉丝，
can I take a picture with your selfie
我可以和你合影吗？”“
yeah boom 10 seconds take a selfie send
好的，10秒钟，拍张自拍，然后发
me an email yes yesterday with a picture
邮件给我。”“是的，昨天我
of the selfie and said we met we didn't
见过他，但没
have a chance to say hi I'm struggling
机会打招呼。我最近遇到了一些困难。”
with I'm and he was quite vulnerable he
他当时很脆弱，跟
told me about some of the stuff he's
我倾诉了他的一些经历，
going through and said I'm struggling
说：“我很难过，
and uh would you mind doing a 10 or 15
你能帮帮我吗？” 跟我通个10到15
minute call with me and he includes a
分钟的电话，他还发了张
picture of me and him how the [__] am I
我们俩的合照，我怎么可能拒绝呢？
going to say no to that right anyway
反正，
there you know there's all sorts of
你知道，这里面有很多
tricks and trades but the willingness to
技巧和诀窍，但愿意
take that risk the willingness to reach
承担风险，愿意主动和
out to strangers that's the key to
陌生人交流，这才是
success that's I mean it's the reason I
成功的关键。我的意思是，这就是我为什么
have kids it's the reason I'm wealthy
有孩子，为什么我这么富有。
um nothing wonderful is going to happen
嗯，不
to you without uh uh taking an
冒点
uncomfortable risk so I think about this
风险，就不会有什么好事发生。所以我经常拿
with my boys I used to force them or ask
我的儿子们来做这件事。以前每次出门，我都会强迫他们或者让
them to speak to a stranger every time
他们跟陌生人说话。
we were outside of the house my oldest
我大
one has no problem my youngest one
儿子没问题，小儿子
doesn't like it really hard okay we sit
不太喜欢，真的很难。好吧，我们就坐在
outside the door for 10 minutes just go
门外10分钟，去
ask them what breed their dog is over
问问他们那边的狗是什么品种，
there just go over there just ask them
就过去问问他们
about their dog because the I think a
关于狗的事。我觉得这
good strategy especially for young men
招挺管用的，特别是对那些不知为何越来越孤僻、越来越不爱社交的年轻男性来说。
isolated whenever you're in a line talk
排队的时候，就跟
to the person in front of you and behind
前面的人和后面的人聊聊，跟
you just talk to them just get used to
他们说说话。 习惯于
opening just get used to eye contact
敞开心扉，习惯于眼神交流，
just get used to being friendly and
习惯于友善地与人
having a conversation because I think
交谈，因为我觉得
people are spending so much time indoors
人们花太多时间待在室内，
and behind screens they're losing the
盯着屏幕，正在失去
ability to establish professional and
建立职业和
personal connection so I think certain
个人联系的能力。所以我认为，一些关于
how to be friendly and how to endure
如何友善待人以及如何承受
rejection one of the most revealing
拒绝的认知行为或训练非常重要。我注意到你身上最能体现你个性的一点，
person is what you just said about that
就是你刚才说的那个
kid that emailed you yesterday mhm
昨天给你发邮件的孩子。嗯，
because as you said I could see the
正如你所说，我能从
emotion in your face yeah look what do
你的脸上看到情绪。是的，作为
you want as a species you want to feel
人类，我们想要什么？我们想要感受
certain things right you want to feel
某些东西，对吧？我们想要感受，
you know the most rewarding things are
你知道，最令人满足的事情就是
Sensations and feelings and I get really
感觉和情感。有时候，我真的会被
moved by these kids sometimes you know
这些孩子感动，你知道，
you relate to them I relate to young men
你能理解他们，我能理解那些
who are struggling because I was one of
正在挣扎的年轻人，因为我曾经也是其中一员。
them and so this stuff really sometimes
所以，有时候，
you know what you want in life is a a
你知道，你人生真正想要的，是
group of people who are emotionally
一群真心希望你
invested in your success and then as you
成功的人。然后，随着
get older the most rewarding thing is to
年龄的增长，最令人满足的事情是
let other people let you be emotionally
让别人也真心希望你真心希望
invested in their success right I want
他们成功。对吧？我希望
my boys to love me but what is the most
我的孩子们爱我，但最令人
rewarding thing is that they let me love
满足的事情是什么？ 他们让我爱
them that's the most rewarding thing
他们，这才是最有意义的事。
right there are these vessels that I get
这些容器让我可以
to pour this like affection into that's
倾注我的爱，
the most rewarding thing as you get
随着年龄增长，这才是最有意义的事。
older so yeah I think about this stuff a
所以，是的，我经常思考这些事。
lot and I get why did he move you well
我明白为什么他会让你感动，
just the picture and I I don't want to
仅仅是那张照片就足以打动你。我不想
divulge but he's struggling he's really
透露太多，但他正在经历一些挣扎，他真的在
issues uh uh with addiction and self
与毒瘾、
harm and depression and and also by the
自残和抑郁作斗争。而且，顺便说一句，他显然是
way is obviously a very talented kid is
个非常有才华的孩子，
very smart is working in you know has a
非常聪明，在一家公司工作，你知道，他有一份备受
high-profile job and is struggling with
瞩目的工作，却在与
addiction and self harm I mean and you
毒瘾和自残作斗争。我的意思是，你会
think Jesus this [__] is real right this
想，天哪，这太真实了，对吧？这
is really really tough for this kid and
对这个孩子来说真的非常非常艰难。
uh you just realize I think so many
你会意识到，
people we're raising my colleague at NYU
我们养育的很多年轻人……我在纽约大学的同事
wrote this book that's this is the book
写了一本书，这本书是
we wish we'd written U the anxious
我们真希望自己写的——《焦虑的
generation Jonathan Hyde oh yeah that's
一代》，乔纳森·海德。哦，是的，这
literally the most infu he's now the
简直是最具影响力的，他现在可能是
most influential scholar probably
最具影响力的学者了。
globally and the takeaway is we're
放眼全球，我们面临的问题是，
raising despite our prosperity in the US
尽管美国经济繁荣，
history and you can just sense it
但我们却在培养历史上最焦虑、最抑郁、最肥胖、最容易上瘾的一代人。你能真切地感受到这一点，
there's so many young people out there
很多年轻人都在
that are really struggling that aren't
苦苦挣扎，他们不快乐，
happy that don't have the opportunities
没有我们
that my generation had and then time 210
这代人曾经拥有的机会。然后，
times a day they're reminded that
他们每天210次被提醒自己
they're not doing well as someone else
做得不够好，因为别人会
vomits their FA success and experiences
炫耀自己的成功和经历，让他们觉得自己一事无成。“
all over them that oh wait I didn't make
哦，等等，我没赚到，我
I didn't I didn't make a million dollars
没在英伟达赚到一百万美元，
in Nvidia and I'm not parting in Sant
我也没在
Trope I'm a failure right and there
圣特罗佩（Sant Trope）开派对，我是个失败者，对吧？”
there are opportunities for professional
职业
and romantic success are going down
和爱情方面的机会都在减少，
people aren't dating one out of three
人们不再约会，
men under the age of 30 has a girlfriend
30岁以下的男性中只有三分之一有女朋友。是的，这样的例子
yeah I mean there's just so many you can
太多了，你能
just tell young people are really really
感觉到年轻人真的非常非常
struggling and I think about that a lot
挣扎。我经常思考这个问题，
and uh you know it moves me because a
它让我很感动，因为
few fortunate decisions a few random
几个幸运的决定，几封偶然的
emails you know things could have been
邮件，我的人生本来可以
much different for me and I I so I
截然不同。所以，我
really I do relate to these especially
真的…… 我尤其能理解这些
to young men I relate to the struggles
年轻人
facing you you talked about making
面临的困境。你刚才谈到了
decisions in the algebra of wealth um
在财富的代数中做出决策，嗯，
and I get asked this a lot um kids come
我经常被问到这个问题。孩子们会在
up to me at the end of a talk that I do
我演讲或
or some other event and will ask me
其他活动结束后走过来问我
about decisions like yeah jump off
关于决策的问题，比如
points in their life as you zoom out on
人生中的一些关键节点。从长远来看，人生中有很多决策的起点，比如
about how to be a great decision maker
如何才能在50年的人生中成为一个优秀的决策者。有什么方法可以让我
there anything about how to make a
做出正确的
decision greatness is in the agency of
决定吗？伟大在于他人的行动力。
others you you're not this B the
你不是B，
business you built is not going to get
你创建的公司
Beyond a certain point unless you have
如果不能
the ability to attract and retain really
吸引和留住真正的
talented people great decisions are in
人才，就无法发展到一定程度。伟大的决策在于
the agency of others we have some weird
他人的行动力。我们对领导力有一些奇怪的
notion of leadership I used to think
理解。
leadership when I was a younger man was
我年轻的时候认为领导力就是
quickly assessing the situation deciding
快速评估形势，决定
what we should do and then advocating
我们应该做什么，然后
for my course of action that was
为我的行动方案辩护。这就是
leadership and it was more important to
领导力。对
me to be right than effective or to get
我来说，正确比有效更重要，或者让
people to agree with my decision than to
别人同意我的决定比
make the right decision what you want is
做出正确的决定更重要。你想要的是做出
you want to get to the correct decision
正确的决定。 为了对
that has the best outcome for everybody
每个人都有好处，要
and be open to change and
乐于接受改变和
evolving and the way you do that I don't
发展。我
make a big decision now without speaking
现在做重大决定
to at least three people so you want to
至少要和三个人商量。如果你想
make better decisions then slow the
做出更好的决定，那就放慢节奏，既要考虑慢思考，也要考虑快
thinking and get the benefit of other
思考，并借鉴
people and expertise is there any
他人的经验和专业知识。有没有什么
decision that I should make slow versus
决定应该慢做还是
fast is there a framework for how to
快做？有没有什么框架可以帮助我们判断什么才是好的？
know what you sometimes I think I find
有时候，我觉得
in business that the cost is the time I
在商业中，成本在于我
waste trying to make the decision and
浪费在做决定上的时间，而
then sometimes in business the cost is
有时候，成本则在于
the outcome of the decision well yeah
决定的结果。是的，
there's been books written about this
关于这方面的书已经有很多了，
but basically every day there's
但基本上，你每天都要
have to make instantly like do I go on
立即做出成千上万个决定，比如：我
the red light do I not go do I you know
闯红灯吗？我还是不闯？你知道，
there's a ton of things you have to do
有很多事情你必须做，比如：
saying thank you pardon me whatever
谢谢，对不起等等。
there's a ton of decisions you have to
你
make every day so we get into a
每天都要做出很多决定。所以我们有时会陷入一种思维定
framework of sometimes where we don't
式，没有
slow down and have the luxury of making
放慢速度，也就没有时间做出
a good decision the other thing is that
好的决定。
I've tried to do is I try to screen out
我尝试做的另一件事是，我会筛选掉
unimportant decisions and this is a
不重要的决定。这是一种
luxury but as I've gotten a little bit
奢侈，但随着我不断深入思考，我发现…… 手头有点紧，
of money I don't make decisions around
我什么都不做决定。
anything I mean this sounds weird I
我知道这听起来很奇怪，但
don't order when I'm in a restaurant I
我在餐厅里不点菜，
don't order I basically ask the waiter
基本上都是让服务员帮我点。
to order for me I have a uniform at work
我在工作时有制服，
I don't pick out my own clothes I have a
不用自己挑选衣服，我有一个
group of people who manage you know I'm
团队负责管理。你知道，我会说，
like you're in charge of all decisions
你们负责这里所有的决定。
here I try to focus only on the
我尽量只专注于那些
decisions I can bring a lot of value to
我能做出很大价值的决定，
so I can spend a lot of time being
这样我就可以花很多时间
really thoughtful about them um but
认真思考。嗯，但
generally speaking for a young person
总的来说，对于一个
that's not in the position of
没有
Outsourcing a lot of decision- making
太多决策权的年轻人来说，
what I would say is get a kit again goes
我的建议是组建一个团队。这又
back to the notion of a kitchen cabinet
回到了“厨房橱柜”的概念，
get a group of people who will you might
找一群人，他们最终可能会和你意见
end up at the same place but they'll say
一致，但他们会问你：
have you thought about this or why
你有没有想过这个问题？或者，
wouldn't you just do why wouldn't you
你为什么不直接做某事？或者，你为什么不直接
just have you know do XY or Z or I think
做某事？我认为，那些
you know who have the leadership skills
拥有领导能力
and know you well enough to go you know
并且足够了解你的人会说：“
Stephen I think you're making a mistake
斯蒂芬，我觉得你在这里犯了个错误。”我
here when I was 26 I started a company
26岁的时候创办了一家
called profit brand strategy strategy
名为“利润品牌战略”的公司。
firm 6 years later when I was 33 I was
六年后，我33岁的时候，
it uh from Sapient Nitro and another
Sapient Nitro和另一家
firm called scient 55 million I owned 60
叫Scient的公司出价5500万美元收购我的战略咨询公司。我拥有
70% of the company so I would have been
该公司60%到70%的股份，所以
going to be worth a billion I if I just
如果当时我接受了，我早就成功了。但我当时的想法是：不，这是互联网，它将会非常巨大，我们会价值十亿美元。如果我当时
had a board if I just called a couple
有个董事会，如果我当时给几个
people they would I know they would have
人打个电话，我知道他们肯定会
said what the [__] you thinking I was
说：你在想什么？我当时
doing 3 million a year Consulting and
一年才做300万美元的咨询工作，而
this firm offered me $55
这家公司却出价5500
million if I had just talked to someone
万美元。如果我当时跟人谈谈，
they kind of got let me get okay so
他们肯定会觉得我疯了。好吧，
Scott you've been offered 18 times
斯科特，你被
revenues for a small strategy Services
一家小型战略服务
Company also around relationships right
公司以18倍的营收收购了。还有关于人际关系的问题。
when I talk to some of my friends or
当我跟一些朋友或者我
younger men I know who are really upset
认识的年轻人谈起
with their spouse I'm like be
他们对伴侣的不满时，我会说：
clear yeah this is an issue but you're
明白了吗？是的，这确实是个问题，但你
not bringing a lot of generosity and
没有为这段关系付出足够的宽容和
forgiveness to the relationship and if
原谅。如果
you don't bring those things your
你不付出这些，你和
marriage to this person or anyone else
这个人，或者任何人的婚姻都
is not going to survive I didn't figure
无法维系。我之前没意识到
this out till I was older but you will
这一点。 直到我长大后，你
always naturally inflate your own
总是会不自觉地夸大自己
contribution to the relationship and
对这段关系的贡献，同时
some and and diminish
贬低
theirs and the relationship is never
对方的贡献，而这段关系永远不可能
going to be in Perfect Harmony or
达到完美的和谐或
balance so in those periods of deficit
平衡。所以在那些付出不足的时期，
you've got to bring forgiveness you've
你必须学会​​宽恕，必须学会
got to bring patience otherwise no
耐心，否则任何
long-term relationship is going to
长期的关系都无法
survive and also be pretty clear if you
维系。而且，你要很清楚，如果你
split up right now just know you're
现在分手，你会
going to lose 70% of your net worth
损失70%的净资产，
maybe 60 but plan on 70 you split
也许是60%，但最好做好损失70%的准备。你们要平分
everything and then the cost of lawyers
所有财产，还要支付律师费。
and I can guarantee you if you have to
我可以保证，如果你现在要
sell a house that'll be the exact wrong
卖房子，那绝对是最糟糕的
moment to sell it it's just Karma just
时机，这就是因果报应。
Karma so just keep in mind there's a lot
所以，记住，
of good reasons to stay together in a
维持
marriage and try and figure it out is
婚姻有很多好处，试着去思考
marriage good for wealth oh yeah really
婚姻对财富有益吗？哦，当然有益，
because I don't want to lose 50 70% of
因为我不想损失50%、70%的
my money or whatever well you'll have
钱。你会看到有人到处
place say think it's a failed technology
说婚姻是一种失败的技术，但
the majority of really wealthy people uh
大多数真正富有的人都
have long-term relationships and are in
拥有长期的伴侣关系。 在
a monogamous relationship they're
一段一夫一妻制的关系中，他们
married because the team is a fantastic
结婚是因为团队合作是
way to build wealth but if if the stats
积累财富的绝佳途径。但如果统计数据
are true and you know 50 whatever 50
属实，比如有50
whatever percent of people are getting
%的人
divorces doesn't that mean that if I'm
离婚，那是不是意味着，如果我正在
Building Wealth there's a 50 odd percent
积累财富，结婚后我有50%左右的
chance that I'm going to lose half of it
概率会损失一半的财富？或者说，
if I'm married or more well first off if
如果
you have wealth going in get a prenup
你本身就拥有财富，那就应该签婚前协议。
yeah but what I would say is um
但是我想说的是，
and first off that number is a bit
首先，这个数字有点
misleading because marriage is becoming
误导性，因为婚姻正在成为一种
a luxury item two uh it used to be 95%
奢侈品。其次，过去95%
of wealthy people got married and 85% of
的富人结婚，85%的
middle class and poor people got married
中产阶级和穷人结婚，现在
poor people the bottom line is no one
穷人的结婚率已经下降到不到一半。归根结底，没有人
wants to mate with poor men and uh
想和穷人结婚。富人更容易
wealthy people attract a lot of mates
吸引伴侣，
and generally speaking really wealthy
而且一般来说，真正富有的
people I mean there's all this you know
人——你知道，有很多
about Jeff Bezos on a on a yacht with
关于杰夫·贝佐斯和
his new girlfriend and everything but
他的新女友在游艇上的照片，拍TikTok视频很有趣——但
the major majority of wealthy people are
绝大多数人……
actually uh uh stay married and the team
实际上，很多富人都会维持婚姻，而且团队的力量
is really powerful you know we're both
非常强大。你知道，我们俩都在努力
working together we're both making a lot
工作，我们都赚了很多
of money that is really powerful and
钱，这真的很强大。把
steering one set of expenses you're
一部分开支控制在内，你就可以
going to focus on the logistics of our
专注于我们
life or our family and my wife's the
生活或家庭的后勤保障。我的妻子是
professional baller right the team the
职业篮球运动员，对吧？
team is powerful so this notion that you
团队的力量很强大。所以，那种“你
shouldn't get married or I'm not I'm not
不应该结婚”的说法——我不是在
suggesting the marriages for anybody or
建议任何人结婚，或者
stay stay married no matter what I'm not
无论如何都要维持婚姻——我完全没有这个意思。
us that at all but there's just no
但事实是，
getting around it the team is much more
团队的
powerful than the individual and if you
力量远大于个人。如果你
if you break down the numbers of people
分析一下
who are wealthy they generally speaking
富人的数据，你会发现他们通常会
invest a lot in their
在人际关系上投入很多。
relationships wealth is a whole person
财富是一个人整体的
project there's a myth that rich people
投入。有一种说法认为富人
are bad people the Elizabeth Warren
都是坏人，比如伊丽莎白·沃伦、
Bernie Sanders the billionaires crawled
伯尼·桑德斯，这些亿万富翁都是踩着
over other people to get there it's just
别人的肩膀才发迹的。这根本
not true what you generally find among
不是事实。你通常会发现，
wealthy people especially people who've
富人，尤其是那些白手起家的人，
the reasons they're wealthy is they've
他们致富的原因之一是他们
collected allies along the way and just
聚集了一群盟友。 就像
as compounding is so powerful with small
复利的力量一样，年轻时的小额投资也威力无穷。比如，在
some generosity to people when they need
别人需要
help being a good friend occasionally
帮助时慷慨解囊，做一个好朋友，偶尔
checking in how are you doing helping
问候一下近况，在
people find jobs when they lose a job
别人失业时帮忙找工作，
being kind those little Investments you
保持友善——这些你年轻时的小小投资
make as a young person really add up and
真的会累积起来，
you're going to find this I have all
你会发现，我
these great friendships now with people
现在和很多以前并不熟的人都保持着很好的友谊，
because we made small investments in
因为我们在过去二三十年里对彼此都做了些小的投资，比如问候一下近况，
you're doing this congrats on your
祝贺一下
wedding maybe not even close friends you
新婚快乐等等。也许他们甚至算不上亲密的朋友，但当你
wake up in your
到了
50s and you have millions of dollars in
五十多岁，拥有了数百万美元的
terms of a relationship you feel close
财富时，你会感觉和
to these people you feel like a real
这些人很亲近，感觉和
of comedy with them you
他们在一起很开心，很有幽默感。
really and this is very true of wealthy
这一点对
people you want to be put in a room of
富人来说尤其如此，他们渴望置身于充满机遇的环境中，
opportunity even when you're not there
即使自己不在场。
so Google did a study when they put out
谷歌做过一项研究，当他们发布
a job opening for a product manager
产品经理的招聘信息时，
they'll get 200 resumés within a few
几个小时内就会收到200份简历，
hours they invite the 20 best in 80% of
80%的情况下，他们会邀请其中最好的20位。
the time the offer that's made is made
这份工作机会是提供
to somebody who has a evangelist
给那些
Advocate friend in the company so this
在公司里有关系、有拥护者的朋友的人，所以
is who you need to be you need to be
你需要成为这样的人。你需要成为
that person who's like oh there's a job
那种会说“哦，
opening here I have this woman who would
这里有个职位空缺，我认识一位很适合的女士”的人。
be great and then next them you need to
然后，你需要置身于这样的
be in a room you want to be successful
环境中。如果你想在事业上和个人生活中都取得成功，那就
go out make friends be kind invest in
走出去，结交朋友，待人友善，投资
them help them when there's no obvious
他们，在他们没有明显理由的时候帮助他们。
reason to help them and those
这些
Investments pay off and generally
投资最终都会得到回报。总的来说，虽然
speaking and this is not a popular
这可能不是主流
narrative the majority of very wealthy
观点，但
people I have met and I've met a lot of
我认识的大多数富人（而且我认识很多
them are kind they're generous very
富人）都很善良、慷慨、有
civic-minded very good mates so this
公民意识，而且都是很好的朋友。所以，那种关于
Trope of you know of Monty Burns
蒙哥马利·伯恩斯
lighting cigars with $100 bills and
用百元大钞点雪茄、
owning the the nuclear power plant and
拥有核电站、把
pouring you know radioactive waste into
放射性废料倾倒进
the river that's a cartoon the majority
河里的刻板印象，那只是漫画里的情节。大多数
of self-made people who are really
白手起家的富人
wealthy are good kind people because you
都是善良的人，因为要想真正成功，你必须
have to have allies along the way to be
一路都有盟友。
company in your view can anyone become a
在你看来，任何人都能创办公司吗？任何人都能成为
successful entrepreneur oh
成功的企业家吗？哦，
no you there's there's certain
不。 有些
attributes that most people don't have
人具备一些大多数人都不具备的特质，
what are these traits first and foremost
这些特质是什么呢？首先，
you have to be really risk aggressive
你必须非常敢于冒险，
and have that willingness to fail you're
并且有失败的勇气，
willing to take huge risks I speak to
愿意承担巨大的风险。我
people all the time who say well I'm
经常遇到一些人，他们说：“我要
going to go get a job at Google or JP
先去谷歌或摩根大通工作
Morgan for a few years then I'll have
几年，积累一些
the credibility to start a business I'm
经验，然后再去创业。” 我就会说：“
like you're not an entrepreneur most
你还不是企业家。大多数
entrepreneurs 70% of entrepreneurs are
企业家，70%都是
immigrants that don't have access to
移民，他们无法接触到
corporate Britain or Corporate America
英国或美国的企业界。顺便说一句，
by the way if you have access to Google
如果你能接触到谷歌，那么很多
all these kids come to my office hours
年轻人——
when I say kids and mind students and
当我提到年轻人和学生时——都会来我的办公室，他们
they want to ask they don't want to talk
想问的不是
about brand strategy they want to talk
品牌战略，而是
about careers and they say I have an
职业发展。他们会说，‘我收到了
offer from JP Morgan or Google but I'm
摩根大通或谷歌的offer，但我正在
thinking about starting my own business
考虑创业。
and I know you've started a lot of
我知道你创办了很多
business and they think I'm going to say
企业。’他们以为我会说‘去吧’，但我就会说：‘别
idiot go to work for Google on a risk
犯傻了，去谷歌工作吧，那里有风险
adjusted basis the most unbelievable
调整后的收入，这是最棒的
platform for generating wealth and
平台。’” 创造财富、
opportunity and long-term Economic
机遇和长期经济
Security is the American corporation
保障是美国企业的立足之本。
these are unbelievable platforms to get
这些平台是
rich with some certainty slowly and
致富的绝佳途径，无论缓慢还是
sometimes quickly in the Tech Community
快速，尤其是在科技领域。
if you have access to those platforms
如果你能接触到这些平台，
unless you hate it and are terrible at
除非你讨厌它或者根本不擅长，否则就
it you should go that way the majority
应该走这条路。大多数
of entrepreneurs are immigrants and why
企业家都是移民，这是
why is that because they didn't have any
为什么呢？因为他们别无选择，
choice they didn't have access to
无法进入
Corporate America they had to open a dry
美国企业界，他们不得不开
cleaner they had to start a soap stone
干洗店，不得不创办皂石
company entrepreneurship you have to be
公司。创业需要勇于冒险，
risk aggressive willing to take risks
愿意承担风险。
two to be really successful at it you
要想真正成功，你
have to be um a great
必须成为一名优秀的
salesperson you have to be willing to
销售员，愿意
convince people to invest buy your
说服人们投资、购买你的
products you have to be willing most
产品。最重要的是，你必须愿意向人们推销
importantly to sell people on your
你的
vision and believe that you're a good
愿景，让他们相信你是一个
person that if you're successful they're
好人，如果你成功了，他们也会
going to be successful what's the best
成功。那么，如果
way to train that muscle if I'm
我还年轻，锻炼这种能力的最佳方法是什么呢？
young gosh I don't know for me it was
天哪，我不知道。对我来说，
um look I I think the core competence
嗯……我想，如果
you would want any kid your kid to
你能让我的孩子
inherit
继承一项核心竞争力，那就是……
if I could give my kids any skill I
如果我可以传授任何技能，我
remember in the tonus preschools and I'm
记得在托努斯幼儿园……
sorry high schools they had Mandarin
对不起，高中居然教中文，真是
that was just stupid or computer science
蠢透了，或者计算机科学也一样。
I believe that replacing history and
我觉得用计算机科学取代历史和
civics class with computer science you
公民课，你就会培养出
get Mark Zuckerberg you get these
马克·扎克伯格，培养出这些
mendacious [__] who are billionaires
满口谎言的亿万富翁，他们根本
but don't care about the health of the
不在乎
Commonwealth the greatest skill you can
联邦的福祉。你能培养的最宝贵的技能，
develop or that you would want your kids
或者你希望你的孩子
to have that will stand the test of time
拥有的、经得起时间考验的技能，
is
就是
storytelling the ability to craft a
讲故事的能力。讲故事的能力，就是构思
narrative and then convince people get
故事并说服人们的能力，让
people engaged in your narrative and
人们参与到你的故事中来，然后
think oh your company makes sense you're
觉得“哦，你的公司很有道理”。你
not going to come in and say I'm
不会直接说“我要
starting a software company you're going
创办一家软件公司”，你会
to say this is the technology this is
说“这就是技术，这就是
the marketplace this is why Society
市场，这就是社会为什么
needs this these are our unique skill
需要它，这就是我们独特的技能”，
set and you can craft it into a story
然后你可以把它编织成一个
that is compelling right it's the key
引人入胜的故事，对吧？这就是关键，
it's the key to scoring above your
这就是你如何超越
weight class romantically right
自身实力，赢得人心的关键，对吧？
communicating a plan communicating
沟通计划、沟通
kindness communicating empathy
善意、沟通同理心、沟通幽默，对吧？
right any industry Jeet Bas was 1997
任何行业都适用。Jeet Bas在1997年写了一封
shareholder letter you read that letter
股东信，你读了那封信，
you just want to buy stock I don't care
你就会只想买股票，我不在乎
how overvalued it is when you listen to
它被高估了多少。当你听
Jensen hang talk about the future of AI
Jensen Hang谈论…… 谈到人工智能
and biology and Healthcare you're like
、生物学和医疗保健的未来，你可能会想，也许
well maybe I should buy it even though
我应该买入，即使
it's trading at 110 times earnings if
它的市盈率高达110倍。如果
you want to be a great CEO you got to be
你想成为一名伟大的CEO，你必须先成为
a great I don't care if you're my
一名伟大的……我不在乎你是像
Angelou rousi synak or you know Jensen
安吉洛·鲁西·西纳克那样的人物，还是像詹森·
Hong the core competence of any really
洪那样的人物，任何真正成功人士的核心竞争力，
successful person or the core comp Ence
或者说
that's going to get you real influence
能够让你在经济安全方面获得真正影响力的核心竞争力，
in Economic Security is storytelling so
都是讲故事的能力。
minister or a philanthropist is this
这很有意思，因为我完全同意你所说的，讲故事是企业家创造财富的核心，更广泛地说，在生活中，无论你想成为总统、总理还是慈善家，构建
idea to craft narrative but um the
故事都是至关重要的。但是，
average how does the average person
普通人如何
develop that skill when they don't
培养这种技能呢？
they're not a lecturer they don't have
他们不是讲师，没有
students that they can speak in front of
学生可以演讲，也
they don't have a podcast necessarily
没有播客节目可以
that people are going to listen to but
收听。但
if we both agree that it's such an
如果我们都同意这是一项
integral skill the transformative life
至关重要的技能，一项能够改变人生的
skill oh there's a million ways the the
技能，那么方法有很多。
first thing I assign my students my kids
我布置给学生的第一件事就是教他们如何讲故事。
in the class is pick a medium it can be
课堂上要选一个媒介，可以
Instagram it can be X it can be threads
是Instagram、X、Threads、
it can be Pinterest
Pinterest、
LinkedIn Public Presentation speaking
LinkedIn、公开演讲、演讲、
radio podcasting identify what it would
广播、播客。然后要弄清楚
mean to be in the top 1% you can go
跻身前1%意味着什么。你可以
online what are the top % of followers
上网查一下
on Instagram how many followers do you
Instagram上粉丝最多的群体是哪些，以及在学期结束前，你需要多少粉丝才能
need to be in the top 1% on Instagram by
在Instagram上跻身前1%。
the end of the semester you need to be a
你需要成为
top 1% Storyteller on a
某个媒介上排名前1%的讲故事高手。
medium I'm really good at this you're
我真的很擅长讲故事，你也很擅长
really good at podcasting I'm really
播客。我非常
good in front of a large crowd I'm not
擅长在大庭广众之下演讲，但我不太
very good on the phone I'm pretty
擅长打电话，一对一交流也很
terrible one-on-one I come across as a
糟糕。我给人的感觉既
Loof yet insecure at the same time which
自信又缺乏安全感，这
isn't easy to do so I know the medium
并不容易做到。所以我了解这个媒介。
I'm not good on the phone I'm I've
我不擅长打电话。我已经
become a proficient writer I I aspire to
成为一名熟练的作家。我渴望
be a great writer I'm good now someday
成为一名伟大的作家。我现在很不错，总有一天
I'll be great but I know my mediums and
我会很棒。但我了解我的媒介，我
I practice storytelling every day I'm
每天都在练习讲故事。我不是在
either writing I'm either speaking I'm
写作，就是在演讲，就是在做
either podcasting if you're young oh my
播客。如果你还年轻，我的
God the mediums are you good on Tik Tok
天哪！ 如果你擅长TikTok，那就
get a smartphone get a you know iMovie
买部智能手机，下载个iMovie之类的软件，
start editing and every day make small
开始剪辑，每天进行一些小的
iterations and changes and commit to
修改和迭代，致力于
being a great Storyteller and the
成为一名优秀的讲故事者。
wonderful things about these mediums and
这些媒体、
the economy and these Technologies
经济和科技的奇妙之处在于，无论你来自
Storyteller anywhere from any background
何方、身处
and from any location I'm not suggesting
何地，你都可以成为一名优秀的讲故事者。我并不是说
that you that everybody has the same
每个人都有相同的
opportunities but the opportunities the
机会，但机会确实存在。
reason why Hollywood is struggling the
好莱坞之所以举步维艰，
reason why the writers for striking for
编剧罢工
four months only got a 5% increase in
四个月却只涨薪5%，原因就在于
on Tik Tok and 850 million of them are
TikTok上有17亿用户，其中8.5亿是
creators which is a fancy term for
创作者（也就是
Storyteller and assume 1% of them are
讲故事的人），假设其中1%是
outstanding storytellers all of a sudden
杰出的讲故事者，那么突然之间，就有
8 and a half million new storytellers
850万新的故事讲述者
have come into the media market and the
涌入媒体市场。而
half a million in La who think their
洛杉矶那50万自以为是、觉得自己的
work is so [__] precious and are
作品无比珍贵，却还在苦苦
trying to figure out why their industry
思索行业衰落原因的人，却要
against eight and a half million new
和这850万新
storytellers that aren't asking for pet
故事讲述者竞争，他们可不会要求
bement leave or for a trailer with
带薪休假，也不会要求提供
catered
带
food the ability to tell craft a
餐饮的休息室。 要讲述一个
narrative find your medium and then say
故事，就要找到你的媒介，然后说
I'm going to be in the top 1% what is
我要跻身前1%。
the algebra to storytelling if there had
如果一定要用一个公式来解释讲故事，那是什么？
to be one if you I know you've not had
我知道你没
time that's really interesting I thought
时间，这很有意思。我一直在思考这个问题。
about that I think of it as one you just
我认为讲故事就是一个公式，你
have to be a
必须
compelling I mean it sounds terrible but
引人入胜。我知道这听起来很糟糕，但
like I have a handsome voice I was I
我有一副好嗓子，我长着一张适合
have a face for podcasting I've had five
播客的脸。我曾经有过五个
TV shows they've all been canceled
电视节目，但它们都在
within like four weeks podcasting is my
四周内被取消了。播客是我的
Medium television television is not
媒介，电视不是。
you've done really well on podcasting
你在播客
and video right that says something I
和视频方面都做得很好，对吧？这说明了一些问题。我
would say that more than anything it's
认为最重要的是
tapping into people's
触动人们的
emotions like how do you make someone
情感，比如，你如何让别人产生
feel something I mean you want to be
某种感觉？我的意思是，你想
smart you want to say interesting things
聪明，你想说些有趣的话，
but how do you really connect with
但你如何真正与别人建立联系，
someone and make them feel something the
让他们产生某种感觉？
wide space I'm trying to
我试图占据的广阔空间
occupy is I'm trying to be a white
是，我试图成为一个
heterosexual male in his 50s who's open
50多岁的白人异性恋男性，坦诚地表达
about his emotions that's a wide space
自己的情感。这是一个广阔的空间，像我这个
guys my age don't talk about their
年纪的人不谈论他们的
failures they don't talk about the way
失败，他们不谈论
they feel about their kids they don't
他们…… 他们对自己的孩子有什么样的感受，他们不会
talk about you know how devastated they
谈论，你知道，当母亲去世时他们有多么悲痛欲绝吗？这种事在
just not talked about among men of my
我的
demographic that's the white space I'm
目标群体中是很少被提及的。这就是我所
occupying so you need to say okay what
占据的空白领域。所以你需要思考，好吧，
am I going to make people
我要让人们
feel that other people aren't spending a
感受到什么，而其他人却
lot of time evoking getting people to
很少花时间去唤起这些情感，让人们
understand those emotions it's uh I
理解这些情感。嗯，我
think the specific crowds out the
认为，细节决定成败，
general you want to focus on a niche own
你要专注于某个细分领域，拥有自己的特色，对
something right I'm going to be the top
吧？我要成为这个领域顶尖的
1% of this medium and I'm going to
1%，我要
develop domain expertise I'm going to be
发展专业知识，我要成为
the person that understands
了解
Ethiopian cuisine and I'm going to bring
埃塞俄比亚美食的人，我要带来
romance and make people feel something
浪漫，让人们有所感触，
and I'm going to connect it to African
我要将它与家庭、非洲
culture and I'm going to connect it to
文化、
maternal love and whatever it is but
母爱等等联系起来。但
think about it what emotions do you want
想想看，你想让
people to feel and then every day it's
人们感受到什么情感？然后，每天的工作就是努力奋斗，
just hand toand combat every day you
每天都在与这些情感作斗争。你
know before we were off mic you said we
知道，在我们结束谈话之前，你说我们
were both kind of in the last two years
俩在过去的两年里，
both of our careers have sort of hit a
我们的事业都经历了一些变化。 感觉自己达到了一个
Tipping Point I feel like I've worked my
转折点，我好像拼命工作了
ass off for 35 years and all of a sudden
35年，突然间就获得了
went over of success and you said what
成功。你问我成功的秘诀是什么，
was the one thing and I can't point to
我说不上来具体是哪一件事，而是
any one thing it was a series of little
一系列
things it's kind of the Mr Beast secret
小事的结果。  Mr Beast 的
sauce it's iteration every day they test
秘诀在于每天迭代，他们不断测试，力求精益求精。无论是
out a podcast you put out a medium post
发布播客、发表 Medium 文章，还是制作
about AI whatever it is try and find a
关于人工智能的 PowerPoint 演示文稿，无论是什么，都要努力寻找
mechanism for feedback and commit to
反馈机制，并致力于
just being a little bit better the next
下次做得更好。我要告诉你
on a little secret what is in the Diary
一个小秘密——“
of a CO Cup this cup that sits in front
CO 杯日记”里装的是什么？就是我采访时放在面前的那个杯子，
sometimes for 3 hours and sometimes
有时采访长达 3 小时，有时
three people a day and the answer is
一天要采访三个人。答案是
this perfect dead I invested in the
这款 Perfect Dead。我在
company on Dragon's dead and since then
Dragon's Dead 节目中投资了这家公司，从那以后，
they've gone from an idea to the fastest
他们从一个想法发展成为
growing energy drink in the UK it is a
英国增长最快的能量饮料。这是一款
mature energy drink and it is absolutely
成熟的能量饮料，味道绝对
delicious but that's not why I choose to
美味，但这并不是我选择
drink it on this podcast the reason I
在播客中喝它的原因。我
choose to drink it is because it gives
选择喝它的原因是，它能给
me what I call all day energy I don't
我提供我所谓的“全天能量”。它不会像
with other energy drinks if you're in
其他能量饮料那样让我感到能量骤降。无论你是在
the middle of a conversation or you're
谈话中、在台上
in the middle of a talk on stage or in
演讲，还是在
the boardroom the last thing you want to
会议室里，它都能让你保持精力充沛。 你最不想
do is have a crash you don't want
遇到的情况就是崩溃，你不想
Jitters and you need focus and that is
紧张焦虑，你需要集中注意力。这就是
why they now sponsor this podcast not
为什么他们现在赞助这个播客的原因。
only is it delicious but it gives me a
它不仅美味，还能给我带来
significant competitive Advantage if you
显著的竞争优势。如果你
haven't tried it go down to a Tesco go
还没试过，可以去 Tesco 或
to a waitrose or go online and use the
Waitrose，或者上网购买，
code diary 10 at checkout and you'll get
结账时使用优惠码 diary 10，就能享受
10% off and when you do try it let me
10% 的折扣。试过之后，请
know how you get on
告诉我你的感受。
I'm very keen to understand how you
我很想了解你是如何
invest your money so say I'm that I'm
投资的。比如说，我
working at McDonald's like or Burger
在麦当劳、汉堡
King or whatever and I say these places
王之类的快餐店工作。我提到这些地方
not to sort of diminish the the value of
并不是要贬低
the work but because I worked four five
这份工作的价值，而是因为我人生中有四五年时间都
years of my life in places like call
在呼叫
centers and the McDonald's Etc but just
中心和麦当劳之类的地方工作。但对
as that's the jumpoff point for many
很多人来说，这都是职业生涯的起点。当
people I get up to managerial position I
我晋升到管理岗位，
have a little bit of disposable income
有了些可支配收入
now should I be going all in on crypto
后，我应该把所有资金都投入加密货币吗？
or my friend has this company he said
或者我的朋友有一家公司，他说这家公司会
it's going to work should I be betting
成功，我应该把
my money there over the a long-term time
钱长期投资在那里吗？
Horizon where have you invested your
Horizo​​n，你把钱投资到哪里了？
money made the most returns and why
收益最高吗？
should I well just do as I say not as I
我为什么要这么做？好吧，听我的，别学我。
do I always went all in on things and
我以前总是孤注一掷，但如果
when you go all in on something if it
你孤注一掷，一旦失败
hits the ground or blows up you're kind
或崩盘，你就完了，本金也没了，
and you can end up I ended up broke it
最终可能血本无归。99年我就破产了。
in 99 I was looking at Jets by 2000
2000年，我投资喷气式飞机，但
after the do bomb implosion I was broke
之后股市崩盘，我又破产了。后来我又慢慢恢复，到
2007 all in on Tech by the end of 2008 I
2007年再次致富。2008年底，我又
was broke again and what I Le learned
破产了。从那以后，我学到的是，
since then is I've crawled my way back
我虽然又重新振作起来，但
gotten very lucky the markets have
很幸运，市场
boomed but now I diversify like crazy
繁荣，现在我疯狂地分散投资。
what does diversify mean you're never
什么是分散投资？这意味着你在任何单一领域的投资都不会
more than a certain amount of your net
超过你净资产的一定比例，
worth in any one thing and you try and
而且你要
make sure those things aren't correlated
确保这些投资彼此之间没有相关性。年轻的
to each other it's harder when you're
时候更难做到这一点，
young because you may have to go all in
因为你可能不得不孤注一掷
on a house you may have to put every
买房，你可能需要把所有
penny you have to buy your first home
积蓄都投入到你的第一套房子里，
when you start a business when you're
当你开始创业的时候…… 你还
young you don't have the luxury
年轻，没有那么多时间
diversifying you have to I bet you kind
分散投资，你必须这么做。我敢肯定，你曾经把所有精力都投入到
of went all in on this business business
这个行业里。
at some point But as soon as you have
但一旦有
the opportunity to
机会
diversify I'm about to put money in an
分散投资，我打算投资一家位于
Salvador I love it it's totally
萨尔瓦多的飞机维修公司。我喜欢这份工作，它和
different than anything I do that way if
我之前做的任何事情都截然不同。这样，如果
my world goes to [__] again in Tech I
我的科技行业再次崩盘，至少
have someone making money fixing planes
有人在萨尔瓦多修飞机赚钱。
in El Salvador I do a bunch of just
我做了很多其他
different weird businesses that aren't
不相关的零散生意，
related because over time because
因为随着时间的推移，
demographics and Technology productivity
人口结构和技术进步，
does grow up in our economy and the
我们的经济生产力会提高，
markets go up the best advice I can give
市场也会上涨。我能给年轻人的最佳
investment is a lowcost ETF you don't
投资建议就是低成本的ETF。你不想让
want fees to eat up you don't want a day
费用吞噬你的投资，也不想进行日内
trade 80 to 95% of people who day trade
交易。80%到95%的日内交易者都会
lose money you want to be in a lowcost
赔钱。你应该投资低成本的
diversified um ETF what's an ETF
多元化ETF。什么是ETF？
exchange traded fund so they basically
交易所交易基金。他们基本上会
say okay we're going to create a
创建一个涵盖
synthetic of the entire market and all
整个市场和所有
health heare stocks so like I could I
健康股票的合成基金。所以，我
can invest in a tech ETF or a solar ETF
可以投资科技ETF。 或者太阳能ETF，或者
or or I don't know AI ETF let me make it
我不知道，人工智能ETF，我
easy go to Vanguard and I don't have a
简单点说，去Vanguard
relationship with Vanguard spy that's
看看，我跟Vanguard没有任何关系，
the index that tracks the S&amp;P 500 and so
SPY是追踪标普500指数的指数基金。
people the email I get most is from
我收到的邮件最多的是
young men looking for guidance and
年轻人寻求指导，还有
mothers looking for guidance for their
母亲们为
for their sons the second most frequent
她们的儿子寻求指导。第二常见的
email is the following is it too late to
邮件是：现在
invest in Nvidia
投资英伟达还来得及吗？
and the honest answer is I don't know I
老实说，我不知道。我
can imagine a scenario where it gets cut
可以想象它股价下跌
by 80% I can imagine a scenario where it
80%的情况，也可以想象它股价翻
triples so this is what you do you
三倍的情况。所以，我的建议是投资
invest in spy because about 20% on the
SPY，因为每投资一美元，大约有20%
dollar will go into the Magnificent 7
会进入“七大巨头”（Magnificent 7），
because they're about 20% of the market
因为它们占标普500指数市值的20%左右。SPY
cap of the S&amp;P spy is again a basket of
是一篮子
different stocks it's it's a index fund
不同的股票，它是一个追踪标普500指数的指数基金。
companies in the S&amp;P Nvidia is probably
标普500指数包含500家公司，英伟达的市值可能占
3 or 5% of the total value of the S&amp;P so
标普500总市值的3%到5%，也就是
5 cents on your dollar goes into Nvidia
5美分。 你每花一美元，大约有20%会流向英伟达，对吧？
right about 20% is that right 24 25% is
24%？25%？这指的是
the Magnificent 7 the tech companies we
我们
talk about 25 cents on your dollar will
常说的“七大科技巨头”。你每花一美元，就有25美分会
go to them so assume those companies
流向它们。假设这些公司股价
double great you participate but assume
翻番，你当然可以参与其中。但假设
the other 493 companies finally get
其他493家公司最终迎来了
their time in the Sun and those
它们的辉煌时刻，股价
companies go down a half you're still
下跌了一半，你依然安然无恙，依然
fine you're still fine again you don't
安然无恙。你不需要费尽心思去
need to find the needle and the Hy stack
寻找关键指标和高收益股票，也不需要像
and stop believing in a very American
美国人那样天真地认为
way that you can figure it out I of the
自己能搞清楚市场。我甚至怀疑
brightest people in finance and what the
金融界最聪明的人是怎么想的。
the my net conclusion is that none of
我的最终结论是，
them have any [__] idea some have a
他们根本一窍不通。有些人可能稍微懂一点，
little bit more of an idea but if you
但如果你
look at the entire alternative
看看整个另类
Investments industry hedge funds private
投资行业——对冲基金、私募
Equity Funds mutual funds anyone on CNBC
股权基金、共同基金，还有CNBC上的那些人——
if you took all of their returns and
如果你把它们的收益加起来，你会发现
aggregate they are less than the S&amp;P by
它们的总收益甚至低于标普500
the amount of their fees it's one of the
指数，还要扣除他们的费用。
greatest griffs in the modern economy is
现代经济中最大的骗局之一就是
believing that some guy who looks old
相信某个看起来又老又不
and unhappy and has suspenders and went
开心、穿着背带裤、毕业于
to Harvard knows more about the markets
哈佛的家伙比其他人更懂市场。
you all you need to know is
你只需要知道
diversification right
分散投资就行了，对吧？从小就
spy start saving young and then the next
开始存钱。接下来
best piece of advice is if you
最好的建议就是，如果
can if you can force savings 98% of us
可以的话，尽量强迫自己存钱。98%的人
will spend everything we get our hands
都会把所有能拿到手的钱都花掉，所以
on it is very hard to have the
很难有
discipline to take money that is within
自律性地把
your grasp and invest it for Savings
触手可及的钱投资到储蓄
Plan find out at work if they have
计划中。看看你的工作单位有没有
profit sharing or IRAs or rth whatever
利润分享计划、个人退休账户（IRA）或者其他什么计划（
the the I forget what it's called here
我忘了叫什么了），
where if you put some money aside the
如果你存一些钱，
government matches it pensions well not
政府会匹配一部分。
only pensions but there's something here
养老金计划，不只是养老金，还有一种计划（
I forget what it's called if you save
我忘了叫什么了），如果你
5,000 PS through your work the
通过工作存下5000英镑，
government I think will match it uh put
政府会匹配一部分。
in a th000 pounds there's all sorts of
存入1000英镑，有很多种
saving schemes that work acorns the apps
储蓄计划，比如Acorns，还有一些App可以把钱
that round up to the nearest dollar and
凑整到最接近的整数，
then immed immediately shoot it into spy
然后立刻存进去。
try as hard as you can to put yourself
尽你所能让自己处于一种即使你
your best efforts not to because the
尽力克制自己不去投资的状态，因为
majority of us will get that money and
我们大多数人都会把钱
go buy a flat screen TV and when you're
拿去买一台平板电视。
saying investing I think because it can
说到投资，我认为是因为它可以……
sometimes sound complicated from someone
对于一个对此一无所知的人来说，投资听起来有时确实很复杂。但
on our phones now where we can in a
现在我们手机上的应用程序只需
couple of minutes invest in the exact
几分钟就能投资
thing you've just said from we can make
你刚才提到的那些东西。我们可以
an account in a couple of minutes and
在几分钟内注册一个账户，
probably ask for our passport take a
可能还需要提供护照
photo of our passport there's so many
照片。有很多
different apps where you can go in and
不同的应用程序可以让你
invest in the S&amp;P 500 you don't need to
投资标普500指数，你不需要
call someone or know someone and you can
打电话给任何人，也不需要认识任何人。最低
invest what's the minimum you can invest
投资额是
$50 go to public.com you I mean start
50美元，你可以访问public.com。我的意思是，你可以从
with a basic a basic lowcost ETF or
最基本的低成本ETF或
Index Fund s Spy if you want to get take
指数基金开始，比如SPY。如果你想承担
a little bit more risk and you want to
更大的风险，并且想
be in Tech there's all sorts of ETFs and
投资科技股，那么有很多
index funds around Tech you're gonna
科技相关的ETF和指数基金可供选择。你会发现，
every young person especially young man
每个年轻人，尤其是年轻男性，
is under the impression they're smarter
都觉得自己
than they are and that they can beat the
比实际更聪明，能够战胜
market so okay take 30 % of your money
市场。所以，拿出你30%的资金去享受
have some fun buy Starbucks Nvidia
生活吧，买星巴克、英伟达、
Unilever Nova Nordisk whatever you think
联合利华、诺和诺德，任何你认为
you have insight into so you can learn a
自己有洞察力的公司。这样你就能从中吸取一些
life lesson that over the long term you
人生经验，而这些经验从长远来看是值得的。 你
don't know what you're doing and just
不知道自己在做什么，就把钱
put it in an index fund because the
投到指数基金里，因为
marvelous thing about the human race is
人类最神奇的地方在于
we become more productive and the
我们会变得越来越高效，而且
Western economies generally speaking
总的来说，西方经济体在
over the medium and long term are up and
中长期内都在稳步增长。再说一遍，
to the right and again and I'll go back
我得回到
to my algorithm or equation Focus find
我的算法或公式：专注于找到
something you could be good at maybe
你擅长甚至非常
great that has a 90 plus percent
擅长的事情，最好是就业率超过90%的。
employment rate stoicism we haven't
我们还没
talked about that realize there's some
谈到斯多葛主义，要意识到有些
things you can't control focus on the
事情你无法控制，所以要专注于
things you can control one thing that is
你能控制的事情。你能控制的事情之一
within your control is spending try and
就是消费。试着
find a partner try and gamify spending I
找个伙伴，把消费游戏化。我在
Junior and Senior year including rent
大三升大四的暑假，每周只花78美元，包括房租，
because I needed $3,300 to go back to
因为我需要3300美元才能重返
school I partnered with five other guys
校园。我和兄弟会的五个人合作，我们玩起了游戏，看谁
could spend the least amount of money
花的钱最少。
find a partner who's aligned with you
找一个在
around spending and saving right realize
消费和储蓄方面与你志同道合的伙伴。要知道，
no one's as impressed or thinking about
没有人会像
your [__] as much as you are right find
你一样关注你的消费习惯。要从
try and find reward from exercise from
锻炼和
relationships not from signaling wealth
人际关系中找到乐趣，而不是通过一些愚蠢的方式来炫耀财富。
with kind of stupid [__] right I call
我称之为……
that stoicism it's really more about
斯多葛主义其实更多的是关于
discipline develop a savings muscle one
自律，培养储蓄的习惯，以及
an appreciation for time and how fast
对时间的珍惜和对时光飞逝的认识。
it's going to go I was stupid I remember
我以前很傻。我记得
to go to the beach when I was in college
大学时，我最好的朋友李·洛特斯开车来接我去海滩，
and he was scrambling to find $2,000 to
他当时正忙着筹2000美元，想
put it into something called an IRA Roth
存到他当时
where his company a bank he was working
工作的银行的罗斯个人退休账户（IRA Roth）里。
for he was just out of college if he
他刚毕业那会儿，如果他能
found $2,000 they would match it with
筹到2000美元，银行就会再给他配
another 2,000 I thought I said to him
2000美元。我记得我当时跟他说过
these exact words if 2,000 bucks means
这句话：“如果2000美元在
anything to me when I'm older shoot me I
我老了以后还有意义的话，那就毙了我吧。”我现在
have made so much more much more money
赚的钱
than Lee Lotus and he is a
比李·洛特斯多得多，他
multi-millionaire now so am I but I've
现在是千万富翁，我也是。但我
endured a lot more risk and a lot more
承受的风险和经历的起伏也比他多得多，
ups and downs because he was that lame
因为他23岁的时候就是个穷光蛋，到处凑钱。
23 I went out spent my first bonus check
我把
at Morgan Stanley I got $28,000 my first
在摩根士丹利的第一笔奖金都花光了。我大学毕业第一年就在摩根士丹利拿到了28000美元的奖金。
$28,000 check I go out and I buy a
我拿着一张28000美元的支票出去，买了一辆
$35,000 BMWs hung swim goggles from the
35000美元的宝马，后视镜上还挂着泳镜，
rearview mirror thinking that would
想着这样就能
impress people I don't know what I was
给人留下深刻印象。我也不知道自己当时在干什么。后来
doing I figured out if I had bought a
我想，如果我当时花
Hyundai for 9,000 bucks which you could
9000美元买辆现代（
get in 1987 or whatever it is and
1987年左右就能买到），然后把
invested the other 20 in spy never
剩下的2000美元投资到间谍软件上（之后就再也没
looked at again I would have enough
碰过），我现在就有足够的钱买
money now to buy 11 Ferraris including
11辆法拉利了，包括
that new electric Ferrari that for some
那辆不知为何很吸引我的新款电动法拉利。虽然
sense an electric Ferrari anyways you're
电动法拉利本身就没什么意义，但你肯定会
going to love this I tell the people
喜欢这个的。我跟我的员工说我开
Ferrari and I say if you work really
法拉利上班，我说如果你们努力工作，
hard someday someday I'll have two
总有一天我会拥有两辆
Ferraris
法拉利。
anyway I don't have a Ferrari by the way
反正我没有法拉利。顺便说一句，
my other joke about a Ferrari is Ferrar
我关于法拉利的另一个笑话是，法拉利就像
is like having a long consistent
持续
erection I don't have a Ferrari
勃起一样。反正我没有法拉利。
anyways anyways but where were we going
总之，我们刚才说到哪儿了？
realize people aren't as impressed with
意识到人们并没有像
your [__] as you are recog the power of
你一样对你的破事感到印象深刻，认识到……的力量。
time and then the thing where I really
然后，我真正
screwed up Stephen
搞砸的事情是，斯蒂芬，
diversification take some money off the
分散投资，拿出一些钱去
table invest and I'm hearing from
投资，我从
employees in Nvidia we talked about this
英伟达的员工那里听说，我们讨论过
diversify you get it's such a
分散投资，它就像
bulletproof Kevlar for your mental
你心理健康的防弹凯夫拉，
health you get risk-free return nobody
你可以获得无风险回报，没人
knows anything can happen Amazon 1999
知道会发生什么。亚马逊在1999年
again lost 90% of its value do you know
又一次损失了90%的价值，你知道
the kind of mental anguish when you go
当你
into a stock like Amazon and you lose
投资像亚马逊这样的股票，损失了
90% of your of your Investments so if
90%的投资时，那种精神上的折磨吗？所以，如果
you want to have some fun ring fence it
你想找点乐子，就把
to 30% of your of your savings pick some
30%的积蓄隔离起来，选择一些
stuff and it'll be a good life lesson
投资，这将是你人生中很好的一课。
for you you may get lucky more power to
你可能会走运，祝你好运。
you over time you're going to realize
随着时间的推移，你会意识到，从
nothing beats over the long term Warren
长远来看，没有什么比沃伦·
Buffett what the third wealthiest man on
巴菲特——世界第三大富豪——的
the world I'm giving you the same answer
答案更好。
he gives if someone has 10,000 bucks out
如果有人有1万美元
of the invest and he's like lowcost
投资，他会建议投资低成本
index funds it's a two and a half hour
指数基金，经过两个半小时的
conversation concludes
谈话，他最终会得出结论：投资
it put it in thep 500 cost index one I
P500成本指数基金。 我
know it's it's the boring [__] that
知道，正是那些枯燥乏味的事情才能
makes you rich yeah it's also I buys a
让你致富。没错，我也买了
lot of Cs it's the boring incremental
很多C类股票，正是这些看似枯燥但稳步提升的
stuff to move shareholder value MH no
举措才能真正提升股东价值。MH说得对，确实
it's so true so one of the things that
如此。
stopped me when I was young from doing
我年轻的时候，之所以没能像
exactly what you just said is I didn't
你刚才说的那样做，其中一个原因是我
think that the $500 I had or the £500
觉得我当时只有500美元或者500英镑，
that I had was enough to get get started
不足以启动投资。
so I said to myself in my head I thought
所以我心里想，
okay when I get a million I'll become an
等我有了100万美元，我就去
investor and I think a lot of people
投资。我觉得很多人
actually listen to these kind of
听了这类
conversations and go okay once I've once
对话后都会想，等我
month then I'll do what Scott said but
每月有5000英镑的可支配收入，我就去做Scott说的那些事。但是，用这么
small amount of money I wanted to use
少的钱去投资是没有意义的。我想用
this little bucket of sand here as an
这小桶沙子来做个
analogy for this because um my team
比喻，因为我的团队
brought a bucket of sand to illuminate
带来了一桶沙子，用来说明
you invest in these S&amp;P 500 companies
投资标普500指数公司时复利的威力。
and this glass represents investing
这个杯子代表
1,000 a month in the S&amp;P 500 over the
每月投资1000英镑到标普500指数公司。 从
of 25 right but if you left it and kept
25岁开始，12个月后，如果你继续以同样的
investing at that rate by the age of 65
速度投资，到65岁时，你的资产就会变成这样：
this you have Zuma Beach
祖玛海滩（Zuma Beach）……
Z oh my God thank God that's you Jesus
我的天哪，感谢上帝，那是你，
Christ it would look like
耶稣基督！它就会变成这样。
that and this is really what you're
这就是你
saying when you're talking about ETFs
谈论ETF时真正想表达的意思。
well you you asked that question about
你问过那个
the young man who says I'm going to wait
年轻人，他说他要等到有
till I get I have 500 pounds I'm going
500英镑，等到有100万英镑才
start investing the way you get a
开始投资。获得
million pounds is by investing that 500
100万英镑的方法就是投资那500英镑。
we don't believe we're going to get old
我们不相信自己会变老，
we don't recognize how fast time is
我们没有意识到时间过得有多快，
going to go we don't appreciate the
我们没有意识到
power of compound interest don't focus
复利的力量。不要只关注
on your Investments put it in lowcost
你的投资，把它投入低成本、
low energy ETFs start early you have
低能耗的ETF。尽早开始，你还有
time your advantage when you're young is
时间。年轻时的优势就是
time and you're going to get that bucket
时间，你会得到那桶
of sand by the way this right here isn't
沙子。顺便说一句，这并不是一个
a lesson in investing this is a lesson
投资教程，而是一个
in storytelling a bucket of sand I mean
讲故事的教程。一桶沙子，我的意思是，
who thinks of
谁会认为…… 别再说了，
is I've I um I discovered the art in the
我……我发现
science of compounding interest too late
复利这门科学的艺术太晚了，
in my life and I just wish someone had
我真希望有人在我
slapped me in the face with it at 18
18岁的时候就给我一巴掌。是啊，说
yeah it's crazy honestly I probably
真的，这太疯狂了。我大概
started at 28 that's still earlier than
28岁才开始，虽然比
most people but it goes to the notion of
大多数人早，但这又回到了给
back to the advice for young person most
年轻人的建议上来。大多数
young people don't have the discipline
年轻人没有自律性
to invest any money they get their hands
去投资他们拿到手的钱，
on because a capitalist economy is the
因为资本主义经济里，
the smartest people in the world with
世界上最聪明的人拥有
the most god-like technology are
最先进的技术，会给
presenting you with amazing irresistible
你提供各种令人无法抗拒的
offers to upgrade from economy to
优惠，让你从一个经济单元升级到另一个
economy Comfort to add to add flowerless
经济单元。比如，在一分钟之内，
chocolate cake to your order from
从Baltazar Balerie订购的无花巧克力蛋糕。
I'm like oh my god oh wait there's three
我当时就想，我的天哪，等等，还有三
other people looking at this room this
个人正在看这个房间，这个
hotel room and it's going on sale and I
酒店房间，它要打折了，我
better it's so difficult to hold on to
最好赶紧下手。现在想留住
any money you want to find ways of force
钱太难了，你想办法强制
savings a house is force savings to a
储蓄，买房在某种程度上就是一种强制储蓄，
certain extent because people don't want
因为人们不想
to be evicted from their house going to
被赶出去。 他们从家里出来，去
work for a company and getting options
公司上班，获得期权
and getting Equity the gross tax
和股权，享受税收
deferred that sort of force savings but
递延优惠，这本身就是一种强制储蓄。但
you want to as a young person try and
作为年轻人，你应该尽可能多地寻找
Force savings an app that that rounds up
强制储蓄的方法，比如使用一款能将收入四舍五入到
to the nearest dollar and then invests
最接近的整数美元并自动投资的应用程序。
no matter what that is for savings it is
无论是什么类型的储蓄，都
very difficult to take money that is in
很难将
ever comes through your hands and invest
你手头的钱直接投资。
it so find for savings mechanisms that
所以，要寻找从
are taken out of your check find out if
工资中扣除的储蓄机制，了解
your company offers any sort of
你的公司是否提供任何
investment or saving schemes that they
投资或储蓄计划，
match or that the government matches and
以及政府是否提供匹配的资金。
most corporations offer Something Real
大多数公司都会提供一些投资或储蓄计划。关于
Estate I've had a lot of guests talk to
房地产，我有很多嘉宾和
me like Morgan howel and others that
我讨论过，比如摩根·豪厄尔和其他一些人，他们对
real estate is a good
房地产是否是一项好的
investment what's your thoughts on it
投资持有不同的看法。你对此有什么看法？
should I be investing in real estate
我应该投资房地产吗？
well you know my brother said to me when
你知道，我哥哥在
I was 25 he said Steve if everybody is
我25岁的时候对我说：“史蒂夫，如果每个人都在
playing the game the returns probably
玩这个游戏，回报可能
aren't great from it goes back to sex
不会很高。”这又回到了房地产的
appeal too much Capital going
吸引力上来，投入了太多的资金。
in look Cas Schiller the brightest
卡斯·席勒，
people in real estate will say if you
房地产界最聪明的人会说，如果你
really account for maintenance and
真的考虑到房地产的维护和
upkeep that real estate has not
保养成本，你会发现…… 虽然房地产的表现并未
outperformed other asset classes the
优于其他资产类别，但
reason I like real estate is that one in
我喜欢房地产的原因是，在
the United States is very tax advantag
美国，房地产的税收优惠非常显著。
there are very few asset classes you can
很少有其他资产类别能像房地产那样，以
lever up 4 to one 20% % down payment I
4倍杠杆、20%的首付就能实现如此高的收益。我
can't buy Apple I can't buy $100 worth
买不起苹果股票，我不可能用
of Apple stock for 20 bucks so it's it's
20美元买到价值100美元的苹果股票，所以房地产的
huge leverage the interest on that is
杠杆作用非常巨大。而且，房地产的利息收入还可以
tax deductible in addition if you sell a
抵税。此外，如果你卖掉
home this is true in the US I don't in
房子，在美国是这样，
the US uh I don't know in the UK if you
在英国则不然。如果你
buy a home and sell it after hold on to
买房后持有
it for at least two years you get a
至少两年再卖掉，就能获得
$250,000 tax deduction 500,000 for
25万美元的税收抵免，
married so if you have for example any
已婚人士可获得50万美元。所以，如果你有
ability get to know the the homes in
能力，不妨了解一下你所在地区的房产市场，
find a nice home or a rental unit that
找到一套不错的房子或一套
you can maybe rent out or or upgrade
可以出租的公寓，或者升级一下。
maybe you're handy to do that every few
也许你很擅​​长每隔
years and take advantage of the tax
几年就进行一次这样的操作，利用税收
deduction and then roll into something
抵免，然后再投资
bigger and that is for savings you know
更大的房产。这笔钱可以用来储蓄，因为你知道，
that mortgage payment is coming every
每个月都要支付房贷，
month actually the majority of savings
实际上，大部分的储蓄都用于养育
for Baby Boomers right now is in their
孩子。 现在，婴儿潮一代都住在自己的
homes it's the equity in their homes now
房子里，他们现在拥有的是房屋净值。
unfortunately that's there's some bad
不幸的是，这其中存在一些
things we haven't improved housing
问题。我们没有像
permits as quickly as we should which is
应该的那样迅速地改进住房许可，这
made it more expensive for entrance
使得年轻人买房的成本更高，他们买不起
young people can't afford homes the
房。
the pandemic in the US and if you look
在美国，疫情期间平均房价从290美元涨到了420美元。如果你
at interest rates it means the average
看看利率，这意味着平均
mortgage payments gone from $1,100 to
抵押贷款月供从1100美元涨到了
$2,300 so it used to be two-thirds of
2300美元。以前，三分之二的
America could afford a home now it's
美国人都能买得起房，现在只有
onethird I I whole other talk show but I
三分之一了。我之前
just did a Ted Talk on the war on the
做过一个关于
young economically but real estate is a
年轻人经济困境的TED演讲，但房地产是一个
very tax advantage industry it is for
非常有利可图的行业，它有利于
savings also there is some I think
储蓄。我认为，房子还有一些
psychic value which I think is important
心理价值，这很重要。当
to to a home you start investing in it
你开始投资、
fixing it up it feels like I don't know
修缮房子时，你会感觉……我不知道，就是觉得很有
it's just there's something rewarding
成就感。
about it but to what your brother said
但就像你哥哥说的，
when everyone's trying to buy homes in
当每个人都想在
an area that usually means it's probably
一个地区买房时，通常意味着该地区的房价可能
getting overvalued and like any other
被高估了。就像任何其他
asset class uh it can lose money but the
资产类别一样， 买房可能会亏钱，但
reason I like it is because it is a form
我喜欢买房的原因是它是一种
of force savings people generally
强制储蓄的方式。一般来说，人们
speaking will make that mortgage payment
会支付房贷，
or try and figure out way now you want
或者想办法省钱。你要
to make sure that not more than 40% of
确保房贷支出不超过收入的40%，
otherwise it's just going to be your
否则房子就会成为你的
anchor it's just going to be a source of
负担，成为
stress for you and I think a lot of
你的压力源。很多
people grow up thinking I have to have a
人从小就觉得“我必须拥有一套
home and so they just become over
房子”，结果导致他们过度
levered in their home and they become
负债，成了“房奴”。他们
kind of house poor they own a house and
拥有一套房子，仅此而已，
that's it and they can't afford to do
他们负担不起
anything else and they might not be able
其他任何事情，甚至可能
to able to move then and you talked
无法搬家。你刚才提到了
about geographical opportunity when
地理位置的机遇，
you're young that's right you get tied
年轻的时候确实容易被束缚，
you get tied down especially if your
尤其是在
home goes down in value but I still
房价下跌的情况下。但我仍然
think it's a in the US at least real
认为，至少在美国，
estate's the most tax advantage and if
房地产是税收优惠最大的投资方式。如果
you own commercial real estate in the US
你在美国拥有商业地产，
you can depreciate It 2 or 3% a year you
每年可以折旧2%或
can't depreciate a stock 2 or 3% a year
3%，而股票却不能。那么，究竟哪些
is there someone that should and
人应该买房，哪些人
shouldn't buy a home then in your view
不应该买房呢？ 在你看来，
is there a certain demographic or age or
是否存在某个特定人群、年龄段或
person with a certain talent that
拥有某种特殊才能的人
shouldn't shouldn't buy a home I would
不应该买房？我的建议是，
say in general if it's a home if you
一般来说，如果你
think that you're not going to be able
认为自己无法持有
to hold on to it for at least seven
至少
years if you hold on to a home for seven
七年，那么就不应该买房。如果你能持有
years you should be able to write out
七年，你应该能够度过
most economic Cycles or a economic down
大多数经济周期，包括经济衰退
cycle um I think there's some wonderful
周期。嗯，我认为租房也有一些好处，比如
things about renting you can slam your
你可以随时把
keys down and leave if you're planning
钥匙扔在门外。 如果你打算
move um if you don't have somewhat
搬家，那就赶紧搬走。如果你没有比较
reliable sources of income um a morgage
稳定的收入来源，房贷可能就比较
is probably a tough thing I don't know I
棘手了。我不知道，
think I think home
我觉得
ownership I'm talking my own book a
拥有房产这件事……我在这里有点儿自说自话了，
little bit here because I've made good
因为我
money in real estate I've really enjoyed
在房地产领域赚了不少钱，我真的很享受这个过程。
it but I think it's situational and it
但我认为这要视情况而定，关键在于
goes back to that notion of having a
要有一个可以为
you on on on that asset class
你提供这类资产建议的“智囊团”。
unfortunately that asset class has
不幸的是，这类资产的价格已经高得离谱，
expensive that the quote unquote
所谓的“
American dream of owning home has become
美国梦”——拥有自己的房子——对很多年轻人来说已经变成了
somewhat of a hallucination if you will
一种幻觉，
or a fantasy for a lot of young people
或者说是一种幻想。
the other thing I I came to learn is I
我后来学到的另一件事是，当我
got money and I it was almost like
有了钱之后，就像
someone pulled a curtain back for me is
有人为我揭开了帷幕一样，我才意识到
how wealthy
富人是如何
individuals play the tax game oh my gosh
玩转税务游戏的。天哪，
person has no idea what's going on got
普通人根本不知道这其中的门道。
to talk about money tax avoidance is a
说到钱，避税是
key skill to Building Wealth and by the
积累财富的关键技能。
way we don't talk about I I speak openly
顺便说一句，我们不谈论……我公开
about my I won't call it tax avoidance
谈论我的……我不会称之为避税，
but my Tax Strategies if you're you know
但是…… 我的税务策略，如果你知道，
it's like they said if you're a prison
就像他们说的，如果你是
of War you have an obligation to escape
战俘，你有义务逃跑；
if you're trying to build wealth you
如果你想积累财富，你
have an obligation to pay as little tax
有义务尽可能少缴税，当然要
as possible do it legally but Apple will
合法地去做。但苹果公司会把
issue their IP to Apple International in
他们的知识产权授权给位于爱尔兰的苹果国际公司，
Ireland and then they will use apple
然后苹果
Ireland they will license their IP to
国际公司再把这些知识产权授权给
America charart them tens of billions of
美国，从而赚取数百亿
dollars thereby increasing the income of
美元，这样一来，
Apple Ireland at a lower tax rate and
苹果国际公司就能以较低的税率增加其在美国的收入，同时
decreasing the income in the us thereby
降低其在美国的收入，从而
lowering their overall tax rate that is
降低其整体税率。这
pure tax
纯粹是避税。
avoidance every organization every
每个组织、每个
corporation does this to the hilt and so
公司都在竭尽全力地这样做，
should you by the way I will vote for
你也应该这样做。顺便说一句，我会投票给那些支持
people who have an alternative minimum
替代性最低
tax we have to raise taxes on
税的人。我们必须提高
corporations the 25 wealthiest Americans
企业税。美国最富有的25人
pay between 6 and 8% tax rate what are
缴纳的税率在6%到8%之间。
the tax games they're playing oh this
他们玩的是什么避税游戏？哦，这是
the rich people there's a bunch of them
富人，他们有很多。
first and foremost it's you buy stocks
首先，他们买股票，但从
you never sell them you borrow against
不卖，而是用股票作抵押借款。
them okay explain that to me like I'm a
好，给我解释一下，就像我是个
10-year-old so sure you own $100 an
10岁的孩子一样。所以，你拥有价值100美元的
Amazon stock yeah you need money to buy
亚马逊股票，是的，你 需要钱买
something instead of selling the stock
东西而不是卖掉股票，如果股票
and it say it's gone up 50% say it's
上涨了50%，或者说
doubled you would have to realize a
翻了一番，你就得实现
capital gain and pay long-term capital
资本利得，还要为
gains on that $50 gain no just borrow
这50美元的收益缴纳长期资本利得税。不，你可以用股票做抵押借款，让
against it and let the stock continue to
股票继续增值，
grow and you pay a little bit of
你只需要支付一点
Interest hopefully from your current
利息，最好是用你目前的
income but basically it's invest borrow
收入来支付。但基本上就是投资，用股票做抵押借款，
put it into a a trust and then pass it
然后把它放到信托里，再传给
on to your kids there's a lot of um
你的孩子。有很多
State Arbitrage Jeff Bezos just moved to
州套利的例子。杰夫·贝佐斯刚搬到
Florida to spend more time with Dad
佛罗里达，是为了多陪陪他爸爸，这难道不
isn't that sweet Stephen isn't that nice
暖心吗？斯蒂芬·贝佐斯也没那么好，
no it has nothing to do with his father
不，这跟他爸爸没关系，别
give me a [__] break he aggregated
开玩笑了。他积累了
$160 billion in wealth he would pay
1600亿美元的财富，在华盛顿州他还要再交
about another eight or 10% in state
8%到10%的州
taxes in Washington because he's got to
税，因为他要
leverage the public school system the
利用公立学校系统、
University of Washington the Seattle
华盛顿大学、西雅图-
Tacoma Airport the hospital system but
塔科马机场和医疗系统。但
in the US you're allowed to pece out to
在美国，你可以搬到
Texas or Florida and pay no income tax
德克萨斯州或佛罗里达州，不用交所得税，
so all the people [__] Post in
所以所有在加州或纽约发帖的人都逃不过。给
California or New York show me someone
我找个在加州或纽约发帖的人，看看
who's CR all of a sudden can't handle
谁能做到。 突然受不了
San Francisco politics I'm going to show
旧金山的政治了，我要给
you someone who needs to recognize a
你们看看一个需要确认
capital gain and has all of a sudden
资本收益的人，他突然就
decided they like Texas politics it's
喜欢上了德州的政治。这真的非常
really not very it's very disingenuous
虚伪。嗯，
there's uh the tax loophole I've
我利用了美国的税收漏洞，有个叫
called 122 or qualified small business
122条款或者合格小企业（QSB）的东西。
so when I started L2 what's L2 L2 is my
我创办L2的时候，L2是什么？L2是我的
analytics company I started it I
分析公司，我
invested a small amount of money um uh
投了一小笔钱，
because it was a business worth less
因为这家公司的价值不到
than 50 million your business would
5000万美元。
if you hold on to that stock in that
如果你持有这家
company for longer than 5 years when you
公司的股票超过5年，你的公司在美国就符合QSB的条件。当你
sell it the first 10 million or 10 times
出售股票时，前1000万美元（或成本的10倍）
the basis are taxfree so the first 10
是免税的。所以
million out of L2 was tax-free
L2的前1000万美元是免税的，
zero that makes no sense if that sounds
零税。这听起来很荒谬，如果这听起来
like we're screwing the middle class
像是我们在坑害中产阶级，
trust your instincts I invested in a
相信你的直觉。我投资了一家
company brought a company out of
公司，把它从
bankruptcy I invested 2 and a half
破产中拯救出来。我投资了250万美元，
million the first 25 million got very
前2500万美元，非常
lucky the company got sold for a lot of
幸运，公司卖了个好价钱。
money the first 25 million were tax-free
前2500万美元的收入是免税的。
these are the tax code has gone from 400
税法从400
pages to 4,000 and that extra 3600 pages
页增加到4000页，新增的3600页
are to turn rich people into super rich
是为了让富人变成超级
people now the myth around taxes is the
富豪。关于税收的一个误解是
following that rich people don't pay
富人不缴税。事实上，富人缴纳的
their taxes
税款
disproportionate amount of taxes so if
不成比例地高。如果
you make all of your money from current
你所有的收入都来自
income that is salary and you make a lot
工资，而且收入很高，那么
you're actually paying more taxes than
你实际上缴纳的税款比
anyone so mom's a baller she's a partner
任何人都多。比如，你妈妈是个大款，她是
in a prestigious Law Firm making a
知名律师事务所的合伙人，年收入100万美元；你
million bucks a year dad's a
爸爸是个
chiropractor has three people working
脊椎按摩师，有三个员工，
for him he makes 600 $1.6 million a year
年收入600万美元，总共160万美元。
total ballers in order to make that kind
为了赚到这么多
of money they probably have to live in a
钱，他们可能必须住在民主党占优势的
urban center in a blue state where at
州的城市中心，在那里，
that level they're paying 4 5 48
他们通常要缴纳4%、5%、48%甚至
sometimes 52% tax rates but if dad
52%的税率。但是，如果你爸爸
decides to raise capital and buy a bunch
决定筹集资金，购买一些
of chiropractic clinics and they become
脊椎按摩诊所，把它们变成
Investments and he sells them for $50
投资，然后以5000万美元的价格出售，那么他的
million is tax rate plummets so you
税率是多少呢？ 税率暴跌，所以你
don't want to be a super earner you want
不想成为超级富豪，而是
to earn enough money to invest so you
想赚足够的钱去投资，这样你
can become a super owner the top 25
才能成为超级富豪。
wealthiest Americans pay about 8% in tax
美国最富有的25人缴纳大约8%的税，对吧？
right so actually the bottom half pay
实际上，收入最低的一半人
almost sow tax they pay a lot of
几乎只缴纳8%的税，他们缴纳大量的
consumption taxes but it's the super
消费税，但真正吃亏的是那些超级
earners that get screwed what I call the
富豪，我称之为“
workhorses but once you makes the jump
苦力”。一旦你实现了
to light speed and you own things and
飞跃，拥有了资产，并
you make your money from buying and
通过
selling assets your tax rate plummets
买卖资产赚钱，你的税率就会暴跌。
there for the average person as well is
对于普通人来说，真正可操作的方法
probably the the first point where you
可能就是你提到的第一点：
said a lot of what rich people do is
很多富人
they'll buy a stock so I'll I'll spend
会买股票。比如，我花
10K on Amazon stock and then I go to a
1万美元买亚马逊股票，然后去
bank and the bank give me A5 ,000 loan
银行，银行给我5000美元的
against my Amazon stock taxfree and I
免税贷款，我就
just hold the Amazon stock now I've got
持有这些亚马逊股票。现在我有
5,000 taxfree if the Amazon stock goes
5000美元的免税贷款。如果亚马逊股票
to TW $20,000 in value then I can I can
涨到2万美元，我就可以
go to the bank and say it's gone up now
去银行说它涨了，
give me another $5,000 and I just spend
再给我贷一笔。 我有5000美元，
and live off that money now if the
现在就靠这笔钱生活。如果
Amazon stock
亚马逊的股票
collapses I'm fine because the loan was
崩盘，我也没事，因为贷款是用股票作
against the stock so they'll sell the
抵押的，所以他们会在股价暴跌的时候卖掉股票把
collapsing to get their money back yeah
钱赚回来。当然，
I mean you don't want to get into too
你肯定不想惹上
much trouble but it leverages how smart
太多麻烦，但这套理论利用了聪明
people go broke but the idea is that one
人破产的套路。关键在于，
of the great tax schemes in history is
历史上最伟大的避税方案之一就是
that stocks grow think of yourself as a
股票增值。把自己想象成一只
stock you you go up in value a million
股票，你的价值每年上涨一百万
bucks a year you're making a million
美元。你
dollars a year doing a very successful
每年都靠一个非常成功的
podcast every year the government in the
播客节目赚一百万美元，
UK is going to take 40 cents of that 40%
英国政府会从中抽取40美分。
of it if you own a million dollars in
如果你持有价值一百万美元的
stock and it goes to two million you
股票，它涨到了两百万美元，在
don't get taxed on it till you sell it
你卖掉之前你不用缴税。
yeah so just never sell it never sell it
所以，永远不要卖掉它，永远不要卖掉。
and that's what elon's doing with his
这就是埃隆·马斯克用他的公司做的。
compan people say he's got you know $200
人们说他有两
billion whatever in fact he's borrowing
千亿美元，实际上他是
taxfree against those companies and then
用这些公司进行免税贷款，然后
when he finally needs to sell it to pay
当他最终需要卖掉股票来
off some of those loans he moves to
偿还部分贷款时…… 他把所有贷款都转移到了
Texas despite the fact he built all his
德克萨斯州，尽管他在加州积累了所有
wealth in
财富。
California smart I think one of the
我认为，
great advantages of life is um as it
人生的一大优势，就
relates to wealth creation is really
财富创造而言，就是
getting good tax advice because I've sat
获得良好的税务建议。因为我曾多次与
that have great tax advice and some
拥有出色税务建议的人以及完全
people who didn't have any at all and
没有税务建议的人坐在一起，结果坦白说，令人
shocking the variance and outcomes are
震惊。结果差异之大，令人震惊——
person going bankrupt to the other
有人破产，有人
person becoming a multi-billionaire and
成为亿万富翁。这部分
it comes down to some of it comes down
取决于
to their tax strategy and how they
他们的税务策略以及他们
thought about tax and have you know
对税务的看法。你知道吗，
being around a lot of people now that
现在我身边有很多
are Masters in tax it was like yeah I
税务硕士，感觉
describe it as someone pulled back a
就像有人拉开了
curtain that I never knew was there and
我从未见过的帷幕，
all these people were doing magic behind
这些人都在帷幕后施展魔法，
this curtain and no one ever told me
而从来没有人告诉我
that curtain existed and it's called tax
这帷幕的存在，它叫做税收。
we don't all pay the same tax because
我们缴纳的税款并不相同，因为
we're not supposed to talk about it
我们不应该谈论它。
again not talking about it is rich
不谈论税收是
people trying to keep poor people down
富人试图压制穷人，是的，
yeah because rich people talk about
因为富人
their taxes all the time brightest woman
总是谈论他们的税收。
in my entire professional universe is a
我整个职业生涯中最聪明的女人 我认识一位
woman named Lucy Lee who is my tax Yoda
名叫露西·李的女士，她就像我的税务尤达，
who works at a big Law Firm that I pay
在一家大型律师事务所工作，我
1,800 bucks an hour to to figure out the
每小时付给她1800美元，让她帮我找到最
smartest when I set up a company I talk
明智的税务方案。当我成立公司时，
to my tax person when I'm about to get a
如果即将收到
big payment from my podcast Distribution
播客发行公司的大笔款项，
Company I talked to my tax person first
我也会先咨询我的税务顾问。
this is it is everything but the key
这就是关键所在。但
when you're young is to become an owner
年轻时，最重要的是成为所有者，而
not an earner you're an earner you want
不是赚钱的人。如果你想拥有财富，就
to buy has to move out of earning and
必须摆脱赚钱的模式，
develop an army of capital that goes out
建立一支资本大军，让它
and kills for you at Night 500 bucks is
在夜里为你创造收益。21岁时，500美元是
a lot of money when you're 21 500 bucks
一笔巨款。到了我这个年纪，500美元就相当于
when you're 21 is 10,000 when you're my
1万美元了，对吧？而且钱会很快花光，
fast so just start and then once you
所以赶紧行动起来。一旦你
become a super owner you have 10,000
成为超级所有者，拥有1万美元、
50,000 100,000 a million dollars in
5万美元、10万美元甚至100万美元的
assets then then you can become a super
资产，你就可以成为超级
tax avoider
避税者了。这
that sounded awful that sounded awful
听起来很糟糕，这听起来很糟糕，
that sounded
这听起来很
awful sitting here with your bucket of
糟糕。 你坐在这儿，手里拿着一桶
sand oh my God a bunch of that's right
沙子，我的天哪，一堆“没错”之类的东西，
talking about this is how we [__] the
说着我们是怎么搞垮
middle class this is how we really screw
中产阶级的，我们是怎么真正坑害
over the little
小人物的。
we have a closing tradition on this
我们这个播客有个结束的传统，上
podcast where the last guest leaves a
一位嘉宾会给下一位嘉宾留个
question for the next guest not knowing
问题，但不知道问题会
who they're leaving it
留给谁。问题是：
for what is the last thing you learned
你最近一次
how to do just because you wanted to
纯粹因为想
learn how to do it that's really
学而学会的技能是什么？这真的很
interesting
有意思。
um you know it sounds this is going to
嗯，我知道这听起来
sound so trite but my boys and I are you
很老套，但我儿子和我……你
know when you get when you're
知道，当你当了
dad you you you if you're an egomaniac
爸爸，如果你像我一样是个自恋狂，
like me I just assume my kids were going
我就会想当然地认为我的孩子会
to be super into World War II history
超级迷二战历史
and Crossfit because I thought oh they
和Crossfit，因为我以为他们会
would think I was such a hero that
觉得我是个英雄，会跟我一样。好吧，
they'd get well you realize if you want
你要明白，如果你想
to be a good dad you have to be engaged
成为一个好爸爸，你必须参与到
in what your kids are engaged in
孩子们正在做的事情中，
otherwise you're just not going to
否则你根本就参与不进去。
engage I have no interest in sports I
我对体育没兴趣，但我
have become a massive fan of Premier
成了
League football because my kids are so
英超足球的铁杆粉丝，因为我的孩子们是
devoted to Chelsea and to Tottenham so
切尔西和托特纳姆热刺的忠实拥趸，所以
I've taken up Arsenal so we could have a
我开始支持阿森纳。 所以家里可能会有
lot of fights in the house but what have
很多争吵，但
I learned I've learned to love football
我学到了什么？我学会了热爱足球。等
and the moment my sons are out of the
我的儿子们搬出去以后，
house I will learn to not care about it
我就会不再在意这些了。
again so I've learned to love Premier
我学会了热爱英超
League football because it's a way I
联赛，因为这是我
engage with my boys well next year we'll
和孩子们互动的一种方式。明年我们会
go yeah I'm a Manchester United fan so
去的。是的，我是曼联球迷。所以，
man you how [__] predictable
老兄，你真是太容易被猜到了，老兄，
literally man you you're such AER You're
你真是太AER了，你真是太
such AIT you you grew up Manchester
AIT了，你在曼彻斯特长大，对吧？
right half my family did so half my
我家一半的人都在那里长大，我一半的
siblings were born there yeah yeah the
兄弟姐妹都出生在那里。是的，
only thing would worse than that would
唯一比这更糟糕的就是
have been man city but you have okay you
曼城了。好吧，你真是太曼城了。
have man you wres then if you're from
如果你来自
manchest I have to tell people this
曼彻斯特，我得告诉别人这一点，
they're like because you get roasted and
他们会说，因为你会被嘲笑。
then you have to indicate that the like
然后你还得解释说，比如，
for me the first place we lived in the
我们在英国的第一个居住地
UK was Manchester so my older siblings
就是曼彻斯特，所以我的哥哥姐姐们都
were all born there and then we moved to
出生在那里。后来我们搬到了
Devon in the southwest which Countryside
西南部的德文郡，那里是乡村，
but one of the strongest brands in the
但却是世界上最强大的品牌之一。
world my my 16-year-old son has a friend
我16岁的儿子有个朋友要
coming they're going to take the train
来，他们打算坐火车过来。
up just to do a tour of the stadium oh
去参观体育场？哦，
really how many many times do you do
真的吗？你们要去多少次？什么时候
that when are they coming oh I think
来？哦，我想应该是
it's in a few weeks we're going but I
几周后吧。
mean we're going to Germany for the
我们要去德国看
European championships World Cup our
欧洲杯和世界杯，我们
whole family our activity is we explore
全家都喜欢去
Europe we follow uh we go you know see
欧洲，我们会去那里，你知道，看
FC Barcelona play I mean this is a
巴塞罗那的比赛。我知道这是一种
position of privilege but football for
特权，但对
us when I stopped playing sports as a
我们来说，足球意义非凡。自从我大学时停止运动后，
sports again for 25 years and now we're
25年里我都没再想过运动，而现在我们
just all in on foot we plan our lives
全家都沉浸在足球的世界里。我们的生活规划
not not around football football but
并非围绕足球，而是
every week we go to a game it's
每周都去看一场比赛。这
wonderful I'm convinced it's one of the
太棒了！我确信这是为数不多的几个
few safe places that men can demonstrate
男人可以安全表达
emotion yeah it's one of the few places
情感的地方之一。是的，这是为数不多的几个
men are allowed to hug each other feel
男人可以互相拥抱、感受
sad feel Joy 100% but it's I've been to
悲伤、感受喜悦的地方之一。我去过很多次，
because I'm in the corporate world
因为我在企业界工作。
amazing sporting event the best sporting
精彩的体育赛事，世界上最好的体育
events in the world the Olympics the
赛事，奥运会、
Super Bowl nothing matches Premier
超级碗，都比不上英超联赛，真的
League football nothing it really is
没有。它真的很
special that's what I learned to do hey
特别，这就是我学到的。嘿，
man was super interesting because um
伙计，这太有趣了，因为……
I've read in your work about like buying
我读过你关于
people buying football clubs and stuff
收购足球俱乐部之
like that and they're never going to
类的文章，他们永远不会
make money but the the asset is
赚钱，但资产
basically valuable because someone else
之所以有价值，是因为有人
wants to buy offer Theory and I'm
想买。这就是所谓的“收购理论”。我
getting loads of those offers now to
现在收到了很多类似的邀请，让我
like get involved in football clubs and
参与足球俱乐部的运营
stuff and and actually based on your
等等。实际上，基于你
thesis about men yeah it is act for me
关于男性的论点，对我来说，这确实是
there's there is a thesis there well the
一个论点。这个
thesis is that there's the real thesis
论点是，
the US has gone from 500 to 2500 they're
美国的亿万富翁人数已经从500人增加到2500人，他们都是正经历
men who are in a massive midlife
中年
crisis the way to become the most
危机的男性。要想成为
interesting person in Cleveland is to
克利夫兰最有趣的人，最好的办法就是一夜之间
buy the Cavaliers of the Browns
买下克利夫兰骑士队或
Cleveland if you worth $50 billion why
克利夫兰布朗队。如果你身价500亿美元，为什么
wouldn't you spend 5 billion to why buy
不花50亿美元买下
the Washington commanders or you know to
华盛顿指挥官队，或者
buy I think tottenham's up for sale
买下托特纳姆热刺队呢？我想托特纳姆热刺队
right now I thought I got together the
现在正在出售。我召集了
in the US which is about 14 of us and
美国最富有、最著名的苏格兰人，大概14个人，然后
said let's go buy Rangers rangers FC
说，咱们去买吧。 格拉斯哥流浪者足球俱乐部，一家
it's a publicly traded company I had it
上市公司，我之前都想好了，
all figured out 10 million pound
1000万英镑
convertible note I'm like we
可转换债券。我当时想，我们……
and then guy my friend of mine's a
然后我一个朋友，一位
famous historian of Scottish is like
著名的苏格兰历史学家，说
you'd be the most hated person in the
你会成为英国最令人讨厌的人，
United Kingdom he was they would hate
他们会恨
you you knew nothing about football
你的，你对足球一窍不通，
you'd be some American Idiot over there
你会被他们当成美国白痴。
and I'm like yeah you're right he's like
我说，是啊，你说得对。他说，
just go to Rangers games it's like what
去看看流浪者队的比赛就行了。我当时就想，
are you thinking yeah there's a pain
你在想什么？
equation with buying sports teams
买体育俱乐部就是有痛苦的，
because you're buying a tribe yeah and
因为你买的是一个部落。而且
the chances are you won't win most of
你很可能大部分
the time and then you have to deal with
时间都赢不了，然后你还得应付像
like Dave from I don't know Southampton
戴夫那样的人，我不知道他来自南安普顿，
whose entire life is that football club
他的全部生活都围绕着你刚买的那家俱乐部，
that you've just bought and he is pissed
他肯定气疯了。
and unless you win trophies from day one
除非你从第一天起就赢得奖杯，否则
you've screwed up and who does yeah
你就搞砸了，谁能做到？没
nobody so it's a horrible pain sport
人能。所以这真是一项痛苦的运动。
anyways SC we're
总之，SC，我们
done I am a big Manchester United fan
结束了。我是曼联的铁杆球迷，
and I travel all over the world one of
我周游世界，曼联是
the big lifes savers for me as someone
我最大的救星之一。 作为一个无论身处世界何处都
that never misses a game ever regardless
从不错过任何一场比赛的人，
because nordvpn allows me to watch the
NordVPN 对我来说至关重要。它让我可以
game in territories and in countries
在一些地区和国家观看比赛，而这些地区和国家
where it's often not available for a
通常由于
variety of different reasons but it's
各种原因无法观看比赛。但它
not just about football it's websites
不仅仅局限于足球，它还
movies that I can access and it helps me
能让我访问网站和电影，帮助我
navigate those geographical blockers and
绕过地理限制。
that's why nordvpn are both a sponsor of
这就是为什么 NordVPN 既是本播客的赞助商，也是
this podcast but a lifesaver for me and
我的救星。
it costs the same as a cup of coffee per
它的价格每月只相当于一杯咖啡的钱。
month and not just that when I'm
不仅如此，当我
accessing Wi-Fi networks around the
连接世界各地的 Wi-Fi 网络时，
world it gives me a lot of security
它还能提供极高的安全性，而这
which is something that I think we don't
一点我们往往忽略了。
think about enough if you want to check
如果您想
out nordvpn for a limited time only head
体验 NordVPN，请
to
访问
nordvpn.com
nordvpn.com
doac and you can access our exclusive
doac，即可享受限时优惠。我们的
deal which gives the dire of a listeners
听众可以享受
a huge discount plus four extra months
巨额折扣，
when you sign up to a 2-year Plan and
注册两年套餐还可额外获赠四个月的使用时间。NordVPN 提供
there's no risk with nord's 30-day money
30 天
back guarantee so give it a try that's
退款保证，让您安心无忧。不妨一试！
nordvpn.com
nordvpn.com
doac or check out the episode
doac 或查看
description link below
下方剧集简介链接
[Music]
[音乐]
a
a